<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:creativeCommons="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html"
     xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#"
     xmlns:xapRights="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/rights/">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Content on @AlTobey Writes </title>
    <link>https://tobert.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
	<pubDate>2014-04-09 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
	<lastBuildDate>2014-04-09 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</lastBuildDate>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/getting-started-with-hugo</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/getting-started-with-hugo</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging a bit more often lately and as a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting
annoyed with the limitations of Blogger. It was a fine service for the years
when I didn&amp;rsquo;t write much. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m doing a lot more technical blogging,
I need a more customizable platform to generate my content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking Disk Latency: Setup</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-29-benchmarking-disk-latency-setup</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 01:56:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-29-benchmarking-disk-latency-setup</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
One of the topics that comes up over and over at Datastax is how to choose the right disk systems to go with Cassandra. While Datastax provides guidance on this issue, a lot of customers still want to know why: why not use 3T SATA drives? Why are SSDs so great? What is the difference between 15k NL-SAS and a consumer-grade SSD? To answer these questions, I&#39;m running a bunch of benchmarks on the disks with a focus on latency.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the most important restrictions I&#39;ve placed on the project is that all of the tests in the first series are going to be run on the same machine. It is a single-socket Xeon workstation I&#39;ve had for a couple years. I moved most of my personal data off of this machine for this project because this system is the closest thing to a server that I can tolerate sharing a room with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-I4z0dUXIQXQ/UzDYcCuG7oI/AAAAAAAA3lk/nf4CznZVmoQ/s1600/20140324_133647_Willowmont+Ave.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-I4z0dUXIQXQ/UzDYcCuG7oI/AAAAAAAA3lk/nf4CznZVmoQ/s1600/20140324_133647_Willowmont+Ave.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Quantity&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Brand/Model&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Case&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16811119265&#34;&gt;Cooler Master HAF XB EVO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Power Supply&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817159089&#34;&gt;COOLMAX CU series CU-700B 700W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Motherboard&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/53557/intel-server-board-s1200btl&#34;&gt;Intel S1200BTL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CPU&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/52276/Intel-Xeon-Processor-E3-1270-8M-Cache-3_40-GHz&#34;&gt;Intel Xeon E31270 3.4Ghz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Memory&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820139262&#34;&gt;Kingston KVR1333D3E9SK2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Root Drive&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822148493&#34;&gt;Seagate ST9500530NS Enterprise SATA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Graphics&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814150658&#34;&gt;XFX Radeon 6450 2GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PCIe SSD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fusionio.com/products/iodrive2&#34;&gt;FusionIO ioDrive II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;PCIe SAS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://store.lsi.com/index.cfm/Host-Bus-Adapters/12Gb-SAS-9300-Adapters/LSI00346/&#34;&gt;LSI Logic LSI00346 9300-4i SGL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;SAS chassis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817998143&#34;&gt;Thermaltake RC1400101A MAX-1542&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9846953&#34;&gt;/proc/cpuinfo, lspci -v, and dmesg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s the base spec. For SATA drives, I attached an eSATA port to one of the 6G/s ports and have an tray set up for quick swapping. So far, the hotplugging in Linux seems to work fine. In the picture above, it&#39;s sitting left of the red air can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On my machines at home, I run Arch Linux. This machine is not an exception. It might make sense to use a more common server distro, but for now I&#39;m sticking with Arch and will not be updating the system once testing begins.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don&#39;t have all the drives yet. &amp;nbsp;The FusionIO card is a loaner courtesy of FusionIO. Most of the spinning drives are from my personal collection. Datastax paid for the Samsung SSD. I&#39;ll be buying a few more once I get through the drives I have so I can cover a couple more SAS options and a couple more SSDs. Here&#39;s the lineup so far:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=9SIA0AJ16A6346&#34;&gt;Samsung 840 Pro 128GB&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(2.5&#34; SATA SSD)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fusionio.com/products/iodrive2&#34;&gt;FusionIO ioDrive II&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(PCIe 8x SSD)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822144701&#34;&gt;Western Digital WD2500KS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(3.5&#34; SATA 7,200RPM)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822148492&#34;&gt;Seagate ST9500430SS&lt;/a&gt; (2.5&#34; SAS, will also test RAID10 on these)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822136563&#34;&gt;Western Digital Velociraptor WD3000BLFS&lt;/a&gt; (2.5&#34; SATA 10,000RPM)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822136795&#34;&gt;Western Digital WD5002AALX&lt;/a&gt; (3.5&#34; SATA 7,200RPM, also&amp;nbsp;RAID1)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For giggles, I&#39;m going to add in a couple USB drives, a CF card, and some older 5400RPM laptop drives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At this point everything is ready to go. I&#39;ll be tweaking the machine a little more over the weekend and start testing on Monday. I figure it&#39;ll take a couple days to dial in the benchmarks. If you have any benchmark or drive suggestions, let me&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AlTobey&#34;&gt;@AlTobey&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tobert@gmail.com&#34;&gt;tobert@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrored FAT32 EFI Boot Partitions</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-25-mirrored-fat32-efi-boot-partitions</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 04:49:05 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-25-mirrored-fat32-efi-boot-partitions</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Most modern hardware ships with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UEFI&lt;/a&gt; firmware and can be booted in EFI mode automatically when a disk is found with EFI setup. When I recently put &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; on my desktop machine, I went with &lt;a href=&#34;http://freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/gummiboot/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gummiboot&lt;/a&gt; to try something new and I really like the results.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now that I&#39;m bringing my Xeon machine back online for some benchmarking, I want to use gummiboot there too. The twist is that while my desktop has a single SSD for root+data, this machine has a few more drives installed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-b7VpThnoo9U/UzDYcLLRIuI/AAAAAAAA3lk/_9S6vuJmIQw/s1600/20140324_133643_Willowmont+Ave.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-b7VpThnoo9U/UzDYcLLRIuI/AAAAAAAA3lk/_9S6vuJmIQw/s1600/20140324_133643_Willowmont+Ave.jpg&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The root drives actually aren&#39;t visible in the photo. They&#39;re 2.5&#34; SATA drives behind the side panel on the left side, directly behind the red and black SAS tray.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since I&#39;m installing a mirrored root on btrfs and using EFI, I want to have /boot mirrored to both drives so the system will still boot if one of them fails. The easy way would be to format both and rsync with a cron job. While that would catch 99% of updates, I figure since I&#39;m using this machine for crazy disk stuff I might as well try mirroring the EFI filesystem.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because of the way EFI works, FAT32 is pretty much the only decent choice for a filesystem on the EFI partition (code ef02). Since /boot only needs to hold initramfs, kernels, and the EFI configuration, I&#39;ll simply mount it on /boot as vfat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9754425.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; This is how it&#39;s set up on my desktop. But now I want mirroring. I tried mdraid, but even with metadata 1.0 the fat filesystem can&#39;t be direct mounted. No big deal. The Linux LVM is actually a frontend to a kernel disk abstraction called device mapper. It includes a mirror target, so all I had to do was spin up a quick mirrored LV then dump the device mapper table.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9754543.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; Here&#39;s the breakdown of what the device mapper table says in English:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;0 8192 mirror core 1 1024 2 253:0 0 253:1 0 1 handle_errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Present blocks 0 to 8192 as a mirror with in-core replication log of the size 1024 with 2 devices, 253:0 and 253:1 both starting at offset 0 with one argument of &#39;handle_errors&#39;. &amp;nbsp;The syntax is terse and the documentation is incomplete, so that&#39;s as far as I can tell. Device mapper can do a lot more than this, but this is all I need for now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With the knowledge of what an LVM-created device mapper table looks like, writing a script that sets up the mirror is pretty easy. I&#39;ll throw this into a systemd unit file when I&#39;m done with the setup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9755039.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; With that script written the rest is mostly by the book (&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Gummiboot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;), but I&#39;ll go ahead and test that the partitions are usable alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9755107.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; And with that, my workstation has redundant boot drives and can be set up to boot with gummitboot per the wiki instructions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edit: I may have spoke too soon. Will update again when I figure out why gummiboot won&#39;t run.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running at Night</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-22-running-at-night</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 01:18:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-22-running-at-night</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I&#39;ve been running regularly for more than 6 months and see no reason why that will ever stop. With a 10k behind me, I&#39;m training to do a half marathon. The twist in my regimen is that I usually run at night with my &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samoyed_(dog)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;samoyed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YN37XhU9BRk/Uyzs8HguR5I/AAAAAAAA3gs/OC7NlB2UYkk/s1600/1926210_10152320020202375_1109355666_o.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YN37XhU9BRk/Uyzs8HguR5I/AAAAAAAA3gs/OC7NlB2UYkk/s1600/1926210_10152320020202375_1109355666_o.jpg&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Running at night is a different experience from running under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sun&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;day star&lt;/a&gt;. There are less people, less traffic, it&#39;s cooler, and more dangerous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tip 1: stay on the right-hand side of the road.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you&#39;re going against traffic, the headlights will constantly ruin your night vision. Most cars are set up to shine the headlights a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.popularmechanics.com/cars/how-to/repair/1347221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;little to the right&lt;/a&gt;, which means you&#39;re getting far more lights shined in your eyes if you&#39;re on the left side of the road.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tip 2: thin-soled shoes are dangerous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since I started running, I&#39;ve become a huge fan of Vibram Five-fingers shoes. My first model was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/Five-Fingers-TrekSport-Mens.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Treksport&lt;/a&gt;. I step on a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liquidambar&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;liquidambar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Liquidambaseedpod.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;seed pods &lt;/a&gt;every time I go out. With the Treksports I feel them but it does not hurt much. The one time I wore my pair of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/Five-Fingers-KSO-Mens.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;KSO&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s, I hit a rock at full force and have not worn them since. When the strap on my Treksports broke, I bought a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/Five-Fingers-Speed-Mens.htm?activity=casual&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Speed&lt;/a&gt; and have found the protection satisfactory, but not quite as good as the Treksport.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tip 3: try using a metronome instead of music.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I tried listening to upbeat music when I started out, but it kept distracting me. For me, running is more mental than physical, so this is rather important. I installed a metronome app on my phone and started at around 80BPM, taking two steps to a beat to reach 160 steps per minute. It&#39;s hard at first, but once you get into you it becomes easy to line up your steps &amp;amp; breathing and really pack the miles on. It&#39;s also handy on race day to keep yourself from overdoing it early in the race.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another advantage over music is that the tick of the metronome doesn&#39;t drown out the sounds around you. The additional sensory information can be crucial at night.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tip 4: have a regular route and stick to it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is an unusual one for me. Any time I run during the day, I take off in a random direction and try to find new routes every time. At night, I pretty much always take the same 5 mile route. I know where all of the sidewalk bulges are. I know where people smoke in their driveways. It really helps lighten the mental load and keep me safe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primitive Tooling</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-19-primitive-tooling</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 20:54:14 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-19-primitive-tooling</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I regularly see posts on Twitter about some new whiz-bang shell or vim plugin that automates some task, making it more pleasant. I almost never use any of them.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The reasons why can be traced back to my first job as a systems administrator, where I had to learn Solaris on the fly. I learned most of my Unix-fu on Linux, where I learned on bash. The shop I was working at used the Bourne shell that shipped with Solaris 2.6 and 2.7. This was a frustrating time because many things that were easy in bash didn&#39;t work at all in /bin/sh, so I started &#39;downgrading&#39; to the Bourne shell way of doing things.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A couple years passed and I had gotten to the point where I pretty much used only basic /bin/sh and was mostly happy with that. Then along came HP-UX and its POSIX shell, which is just like Bourne shell only maddeningly different in a few places. Since the environment I was working in had both Linux and HP-UX in production, I usually wrote scripts to support both and it was tedious. I talked my team into switching to pdksh everywhere and things were mostly better. I got a stable environment across operating systems while the experienced HP-UX admins got an experience more like what they were used to on Linux. Win-win for the win.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Eventually, AT&amp;amp;T opened up the code to the original Korn shell and the pdksh project stagnated. As far as I know, it still compiles on Linux, but it did not work very well on HP-UX / Itanium without patches. I wrote the patches, but if you know anything about HP-UX shops, you know that they tend to be conservative so pdksh was out. And now I&#39;m back to writing POSIX shell code.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;That&#39;s just one part of the story, but I think it demonstrates why I still stick to primitives a decade later. With every move between versions of shells, Linux distributions, FreeBSD, OpenSolaris, etc. I&#39;ve simply found it easier to stick with primitives and avoid any heavily modified environments. These days, I do default to bash and use bash syntax regularly. I don&#39;t work on any operating systems that don&#39;t ship bash. I also start my shell scripts with #!/bin/bash instead of #!/bin/sh so the dash thing never bothered me a bit.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My vim setup is similarly minimal. My ~/.vimrc is around 30 lines and has changed very little in the last decade. I added Pathogen a couple years ago, but I only really use it for filetype and syntax plugins. I also only use about 5% of vim&#39;s features, mostly things that work in vi. Just like with the shells, I can log into almost any Unix system around and get up and running with vi without installing anything.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Over the years I have applied the approach to more things. I&#39;ve always used the default clients for social media. I don&#39;t use browser plugins (except for &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/rikaikun/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rikaikun&lt;/a&gt;). I only install a half-dozen or so applications on my Mac. My Windows machines have no OS-level plugins. My preferred desktop on Linux is XCFE with a basically default config, no compositing, all shininess disabled. My phone has a stock ROM and I use the default UI settings most of the time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s not for everybody, but it does have some advantages:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;1.) it takes me about 5 minutes to get set up on a new workstation&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;2.) I rarely have to install anything extra on machines I admin&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;3.) the few rcfiles I use are easy to move around with `cat &amp;gt; ~/.rcfile` and ctrl-d&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;4.) the few aliases I use are noops when not present (e.g. ls --color)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;5.) I don&#39;t have to remember or think about trivial details very often&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Like every decision, it&#39;s a tradeoff. I&#39;m trading off small efficiencies every day to avoid having to memorize lots of things. My editor isn&#39;t as powerful as yours, but I always have my editor even when I&#39;m not root. My shell is boring, but whether I&#39;m root, atobey, or any other account it works the same.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I also tend to apply similar thinking to code, which is probably one of the reasons I like Go so much. A small syntax is easy to remember and apply consistently. I also don&#39;t put as much emphasis on code reuse as I see others do. The backflips required to make code actually reusable is rarely worth the effort and increases testing burden, so why bother? It&#39;s another tradeoff obviously and one I default to with increasing frequency as I grow in experience.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Video Production</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-10-open-source-video-production</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 19:52:59 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-03-10-open-source-video-production</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I&#39;m always looking for new ways to educate my audience and have recently started setting up my workstation for recording video to post on Youtube. While I could have gone down the easy road and used my Mac laptop for all of this, I wanted to see what it would take to make it all work on my Linux workstation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;There are lots of application choices for capturing and recording video on Linux. Unfortunately, most of the user interfaces I tried were buggy or totally inflexible. Being a long-time Unix user, I started looking around for more powerful tools on the command line. I was not disappointed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;There&#39;s VLC and cvlc for command-line work. In fact, VLC is probably the easiest choice for any kind of media and generally works out of the box. I made a couple of test recordings with VLC and it works fine. Since figuring out what to do with VLC took less than five minutes, I figured I&#39;d look for something more challenging and, hopefully, a little more flexible.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Gstreamer is a framework and libraries for working with media on lots of platforms, but it really shines on Linux. It&#39;s meant to be used as a library, but it also comes with a useful pair of CLI tools in the form of gst-inspect and gst-launch. Working with these is really confusing at first since the intent behind the syntax of available examples is not parseable without in-depth knowledge of how gstreamer works. Initial experiments showed that I could do what I want and more. For example, here&#39;s how to record your webcam to a file:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9471907.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had this idea of recording an overhead camera simultaneously with a forward camera, so I decided to invest some time into learning gstreamer well enough to use it. I was having a hard time figuring out how to do complex flows in gst-launch because it requires an understanding of how the gstreamer API works. I decided to try the Python API to see if it was any easier. It&#39;s not Python&#39;s fault but that way lies madness. There are currently two major versions of the gstreamer API available, 0.10 and 1.0. This creates problems for gst-launch and python alike. The vast majority of examples are for 0.10. Packages are available for both. I couldn&#39;t find a usable combination so I gave up and Googled &#34;golang gstreamer&#34;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even though the Go bindings for gstreamer are minimal, I did manage to get them working with gstreamer 1.2 and got an example program going.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9421872.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;My modified bindings for Go/gstreamer are available on Github at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tobert/gst&#34;&gt;https://github.com/tobert/gst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While I love programming in Go, this was another dead end. The bindings don&#39;t have all of the API endpoints I need and, more importantly, &#39;go build&#39; with cgo involved was really slowing me down so I decided to try gst-launch again using what I&#39;ve learned.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9472582.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That works, but what I really want is to do a whole lot more. How about capturing both webcams, audio, and a terminal window all in one go? Yup, it can do that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tobert/9426323.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And finally, here&#39;s the result. I&#39;ll switch to a larger font in the terminal in the future, but you get the idea.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; class=&#34;BLOGGER-youtube-video&#34; classid=&#34;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34; data-thumbnail-src=&#34;https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/JFjIwtbITSo/0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/v/JFjIwtbITSo?version=3&amp;f=user_uploads&amp;c=google-webdrive-0&amp;app=youtube_gdata&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34;  src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/v/JFjIwtbITSo?version=3&amp;f=user_uploads&amp;c=google-webdrive-0&amp;app=youtube_gdata&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage Stuff</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-19-marriage-stuff</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 05:50:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-19-marriage-stuff</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Earlier this evening, my teenage niece posted an article titled &#34;Letting My Wife Go&#34; on Facebook. I gave it a quick read, liked it, then shared it. The link is at the end of this note.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Two people whom I admire quickly called me out for posting something with so little substance. I took another look at it and realized that I agree. It doesn&#39;t have a lot to offer. I was reading a lot more into it than was actually there. Here&#39;s my story.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When Krissy﻿ and I got married, we snuffed the individual candles around the big unity candle. This was to signify the end of the individuals and the beginning of married life. At the time, I remember thinking that the symbolism was a bit silly while Krissy took it quite seriously. Since it wasn&#39;t a big deal to me, I went along with it without really thinking through why I thought it was silly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We tried really hard with the &#34;two shall become one&#34; model for a long time. Because we were both committed to being good spouses, we had a good marriage. Nearly a decade of passive-aggressive battles held our marriage back from being great. I wanted kids. She didn&#39;t. She wanted my faith to mirror hers. I failed. There were other issues, but none of them rated by comparison.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;We were attached to impractical ideals of each other and ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I desperately wanted to be a father. She desperately wanted to be a faithful pastor&#39;s wife. I think every marriage has these issues in one form or another. Some guys wish they were carefree bachelors. Some women wish they could pursue their careers without guilt. It&#39;s all dross.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;d love to say that we&#39;ve entirely let go of those ideas, but in reality we&#39;re still working on it. That said, things are better than ever - I&#39;ll go so far as to say that our marriage is great. She is okay with me being a faithless intellectual. I have come to understand her style of motherhood. Our family has grown and changed for the better.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We&#39;ve learned to accept each other as we are (most of the time).&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While I could frame this improvement in terms of letting go of grudges, that would be focusing on the symptom and ignoring the disease. The problem is unrealistic expectations. The result of expecting one thing and observing another is often disappointment. It makes no sense to hold Krissy responsible for my failure to see what&#39;s right in front of me: a sensual, fun, intelligent woman with her own ideas, goals, and desires. The solution is letting go. Letting go entirely is also impractical, but with practice, it gets easier to do from moment to moment and life gets easier.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I have to let go of the woman I think she could be. Every day. I&#39;m glad that woman is a fantasy because the real Krissy is far more interesting and fun to be around.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Link:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethadamsmith.com/2014/02/14/letting-my-wife-go/&#34;&gt;Letting My Wife Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/03085363965448999111&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Krissy
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2014-02-19T11:54:40.318Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    Awww. This is lovely.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portacluster</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-portacluster</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 21:08:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-portacluster</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The parts are in the mail!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve been excited about this idea for a few years now, but haven&#39;t had a good reason and/or resources to go for it. Now that my work involves traveling around and showing off Cassandra, I need a suitable demo cluster. One good rule of presenting to audiences is to never rely on the internet connection if you can help it. Murphy&#39;s Law dictates that if you rely on the wifi for an important part of your talk, said wifi will almost certainly fail when you need it most.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My original concept for the porta-cluster was to string a series of workstation motherboards together in a shipping case in such a way that they have just enough airflow and cabling to look decent but not hide anything.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gqdi6XTcwhc/UvVJK0xEXFI/AAAAAAAAgZk/Ch1XhmSsPY4/s1600/motherboard-stack.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;background: none; margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gqdi6XTcwhc/UvVJK0xEXFI/AAAAAAAAgZk/Ch1XhmSsPY4/s1600/motherboard-stack.png&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: start;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But that&#39;s still a bit unwieldy with lots of problems such as heatsink/fan size/flow, where to put the PSUs, etc.. Fortunately, there&#39;s a better solution on the market now in the form of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://downloadmirror.intel.com/23089/eng/D54250WYB_D34010WYB_TechProdSpec03.pdf&#34;&gt;Intel NUC&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rjAXqU6U91w/UvVJP94JycI/AAAAAAAAgZs/L07hFC8jN2M/s1600/D54250WYK1.png&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rjAXqU6U91w/UvVJP94JycI/AAAAAAAAgZs/L07hFC8jN2M/s1600/D54250WYK1.png&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This isn&#39;t a new development, since a pile of Mac Minis would do the same thing. I like these a little better than a mini though, because they&#39;re much smaller, about 1/4 of the size, and can support Linux out of the box. I&#39;m impressed that these can hold 16GB of RAM and a 240GB mSATA drive, all wired up to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://ark.intel.com/products/75028/&#34;&gt;Intel i5 processor&lt;/a&gt; and a gigabit ethernet port. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzMppPgLW-s&#34;&gt;For lack of a better word&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/2FDeAqS_cmc?t=23s&#34;&gt;perfect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As people do, I was using Newegg&#39;s shopping cart for R&amp;amp;D and came up with this loadout.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;docs-internal-guid-106eab4e-0e19-e7c0-0b0d-01d603b5f34f&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;table style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; border: none; width: 624px;&#34;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;135&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;*&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;364&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;125&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 33px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Server&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; line-height: 1; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Intel NUC &lt;/span&gt;D54250WYK1&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;374.99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Memory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;2 x 8G 204-pin DDR3 1600 SO-DIMM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;139.99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Intel 525 Series SSDMCEA240B301 240G mSATA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;289.99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Display&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;GeChic On-Lap 2501B 15.6” Portable LCD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;249.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Logitech K400 (920-003070)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;39.99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Cables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1m Cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; font-weight: bold; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt; RJ45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;2.78&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Network Switch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Netgear ProSafe M4100-D12G&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;193.99&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Power Strip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Digital Loggers Web Power Switch 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;139.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&#34;height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Case&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;Pelican IM2950-X0001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;border: 1px solid #000000; padding: 7px 7px 7px 7px; vertical-align: top;&#34;&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;219.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;docs-internal-guid-106eab4e-0e19-e7c0-0b0d-01d603b5f34f&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Droid Sans&#39;; font-size: 16px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;table style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; border: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;135&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;364&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;col width=&#34;125&#34;&gt;&lt;/col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;docs-internal-guid-106eab4e-0e19-e7c0-0b0d-01d603b5f34f&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The managed power supply will make scripting bare metal reinstallation easier since these machines don&#39;t have remote power control. The managed switch provides for two important use cases. The first is the ability to remotely enable/disable ports for partition simulations. The second is to do simple L3 routing between VLANs so I can split the cluster into two 3-node datacenters for demonstrations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, the whole thing will live in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pelican.com/cases_detail_storm.php?Case=iM2950&#34;&gt;Pelican case&lt;/a&gt; that is (hopefully) easy to check at the airport so I can take it to shows.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After going through IT purchasing, a couple things changed, but for the most part this is exactly what&#39;s coming. The power strip got upgraded to a small APC unit and the LCD got left out for now. I&#39;ll probably use my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/6/21/3105822/motorola-lapdock-hacked-raspberry-pi-rikomagic&#34;&gt;Droid Dock&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale12x/presentations/managing-cassandra&#34;&gt;SCALE12x&lt;/a&gt; and find something else later.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you find that the UPS package tracking service is a little slow, I&#39;m sorry. I can&#39;t help myself. The refresh button is there for a reason...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read this NAO</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-read-this-nao</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 20:27:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-read-this-nao</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Joe Armstrong is the author of Erlang, an old computer programming language that was/is decades ahead of its time and is still relevant today. He wrote a blog post that accessibly says something every good programmer understands but finds difficult to articulate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://joearms.github.io/2014/02/07/why-programming-is-difficult.html&#34;&gt;http://joearms.github.io/2014/02/07/why-programming-is-difficult.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;undefined&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Anonymous
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2014-02-07T20:14:58.832Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    Your link goes through facebook.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/04993705361897027137&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Albert P. Tobey
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2014-02-07T20:27:06.868Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    You&amp;#39;re right. Fixing.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日本2014訪問</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-2014</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2014-02-07-2014</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.15; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the best and worst things about being an open source evangelist is traveling often. I am not (yet) a seasoned traveler. Every trip teaches me something new and my trip to Japan was a real eye-opener.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The primary objective of this trip was to speak at Cassandra 日本 2014. IMO it was a success. I already posted my &lt;a href=&#34;http://planetcassandra.org/blog/post/cassandra-japan-2014-recap-by-al-tobey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cassandra 日本 2014 Recap&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://planetcassandra.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PlanetCassandra&lt;/a&gt;. I also planned to &lt;strike&gt;vacation&lt;/strike&gt; attend some meetups, so I stayed there for a week.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I ended up staying in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akihabara&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Akihabara&lt;/a&gt;. A.K.A. Akihabara Electric Town, which hosts more anime, manga, and figma, video games, and electronics than I could possibly visit during the trip. Since I had to prepare for the conference on Friday, I limited myself to one bookstore and one bowl of ramen so I wouldn&#39;t be out all night. Score.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fI-P-xlyeZo/UvP8QA_XBZI/AAAAAAAAgVg/UMzPpDpvSmI/s1600/FB_IMG_13904824056130077.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fI-P-xlyeZo/UvP8QA_XBZI/AAAAAAAAgVg/UMzPpDpvSmI/s1600/FB_IMG_13904824056130077.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&#39;s 3 Final Fantasy soundtracks I didn&#39;t have. I&#39;m a little obsessed with the series and Nobuo Uematsu is one of my favorite composers. The cartridges are Final Fantasy IV, V, Chrono Trigger, and Albert Odyssey for Super Famicom. The Final Fantasy games and Chrono Trigger rank in my top 5 favorite video games, so for the price I figure they&#39;re neat collector&#39;s items.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Since my hotel, Remm Akihabara, is about 2km North of Tōkyō, to get to the conference, I had to take the train from Akihabara station through Tōkyō station to the 24HOUR building next to Telecom Station. Tōkyō is famous for its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b0A9-oUoMug&#34;&gt;train congestion&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s just say that I have a new appreciation for the term “crowded”. While I did not see or experience the &#34;pushers&#34;, it felt just the same.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; class=&#34;BLOGGER-youtube-video&#34; classid=&#34;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34; data-thumbnail-src=&#34;https://ytimg.googleusercontent.com/vi/b0A9-oUoMug/0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/b0A9-oUoMug&amp;source=uds&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34;  src=&#34;https://youtube.googleapis.com/v/b0A9-oUoMug&amp;source=uds&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;During my talk, I wanted to get away from the tech for a few moments and decided to tell a story from one of my Japanese lessons. In one of my slides, I included the phrase “アルトビーの犬はばかね” / &#34;aru tobii no inu baka ne?&#34; which translates to “Al Tobey’s dog is stupid isn’t it?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img height=&#34;341px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/YU8bnR1Vb5rtPaTuhSqRnWQbJsUEoF5ShJikXyBueLrQ1aKhOojKSlhTshzd6aQ8oZ4hGBB6h-YUWtRUkQN7M1VEDg5KK4L2XKxak4wBikoLrLwLJVFvzff8XQ&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px solid transparent; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34; width=&#34;371px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: small; text-align: start;&#34;&gt;アルトビーの犬はばかね&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;b style=&#34;font-weight: normal; margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: transparent; color: black; font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: transparent; color: black; font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: transparent; color: black; font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ran this phrase by my Japanese instructor at one point and learned about a cultural difference. It&#39;s pretty common to say things like &#34;stupid dog&#34; in America, but apparently that&#39;s not a thing in Japan. I had to explain to her how this is a term of endearment. It didn&#39;t work. At least I had a short story to tell to break my talk up a little.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I met some awesome people at the reception after the conference that I hope to keep up with. I&#39;m excited to practice my Japanese with one young engineer who&#39;s also working on his English skills&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On Saturday morning, I got up and had a Starbuck&#39;s breakfast of coffee and a blueberry muffin. I had no schedule at this point, so I took my time and spent some time reading. Since nothing in Akihabara was open yet, I decided to go for a random walk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&#34;center&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;tr-caption-container&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6xGU1yF2rxY/UvQFe19QAsI/AAAAAAAAgVw/_52iRGsYdg0/s1600/20140125_092652_Japan.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6xGU1yF2rxY/UvQFe19QAsI/AAAAAAAAgVw/_52iRGsYdg0/s1600/20140125_092652_Japan.jpg&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;tr-caption&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;A statue near Akihabara&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;This is a stupid thing I tend to do when I visit new cities. I pick a direction basically at random and start walking, turning when I think it might take me somewhere interesting. I learned a bit about Tokyo, the most memorable item being that it is /very/ clean compared to any other city I&#39;ve visited. I&#39;m certain I could have walked barefoot and been safe. I did see a little trash in a few places, but I suspect it won&#39;t be there long. The other thing I really liked was how bicycles had these tiny wheel locks that I could cut with cheap tin shears. They weren&#39;t locked to anything. I could have picked one up and walked off at any time, but that doesn&#39;t happen very often. Neat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After a while, I pulled up Google Maps and plotted a 6km course back to my hotel to refresh. In total I walked around 12km. I couldn&#39;t possibly remember the names of the districts or everything I visited, but I had a good time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At some point I wandered into&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yodobashi_Camera&#34;&gt;Yobodashi-Akiba&lt;/a&gt;. This place is amazing. Imagine if all of the electronics on Amazon were in a&amp;nbsp;9-story building and you just about got it. They literally have everything on the shelf, it&#39;s all neat and organized, and overwhelming. I didn&#39;t end up buying anything except for lunch on the restaurant level, which was delicious, but for the life of me I couldn&#39;t name it. I ordered with by pointing and saying &#34;hitotsu onegaishimasu&#34;. I finished the evening at another bookstore, where I found the perfect gift for a friend&#39;s daughter, who is a fan of Black Butler. (I got her the art book on the bottom left)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gO3QbeVFYCc/UvQQWfwRb2I/AAAAAAAAgWA/A3aqwpWdf4k/s1600/20140125_163329_1+Chome.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gO3QbeVFYCc/UvQQWfwRb2I/AAAAAAAAgWA/A3aqwpWdf4k/s1600/20140125_163329_1+Chome.jpg&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I enjoyed some more ramen and found some more Final Fantasy swag.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3zyTqEIrINM/UvQRO52q9hI/AAAAAAAAgWY/tDCJtc-R7ms/s1600/20140126_110922.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3zyTqEIrINM/UvQRO52q9hI/AAAAAAAAgWY/tDCJtc-R7ms/s1600/20140126_110922.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Zc7oJnhTal0/UvQRNyWOyaI/AAAAAAAAgWQ/PyG3MWF0CbE/s1600/20140126_104951.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Zc7oJnhTal0/UvQRNyWOyaI/AAAAAAAAgWQ/PyG3MWF0CbE/s1600/20140126_104951.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QEPzDvaIPKo/UvQREkKN_wI/AAAAAAAAgWI/58TNrer1eMs/s1600/20140126_104945.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QEPzDvaIPKo/UvQREkKN_wI/AAAAAAAAgWI/58TNrer1eMs/s1600/20140126_104945.jpg&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.15; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;On Monday, I decided to finally get out to Kyoto. I walked to Tokyo station, then rode the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sany%C5%8D_Shinkansen&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;to Kyoto and arrived around 10:00AM. I had no plan, so when I saw the bus tour depot outside of Kyoto station, I decided to give it a try since I&#39;ve never done such a thing before. I had some time to kill before the bus boarded, so what else to do but grab lunch?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3f5Qa_KhUuY/UvQnHkXFi4I/AAAAAAAAgYo/WTv68dTXkSo/s1600/20140127_110515_Japan.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3f5Qa_KhUuY/UvQnHkXFi4I/AAAAAAAAgYo/WTv68dTXkSo/s1600/20140127_110515_Japan.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;Overall, the bus tour was fun! A headset with narrative in English was provided. My proudest moment of videography occurred at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinkaku-ji&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kinkaku-ji&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;temple. Mostly, I just got lucky. I hit the record button in video mode just a moment before a crane decided to take flight. Sugoi!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;object width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; class=&#34;BLOG_video_class&#34; id=&#34;BLOG_video-7f9d3fa1901972ad&#34; classid=&#34;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&#34; codebase=&#34;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;//www.youtube.com/get_player&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgcolor&#34; value=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;flashvars&#34; value=&#34;flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D7f9d3fa1901972ad%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%253Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1399253600%26sparams%3Did,itag,source,ip,ipbits,expire%26signature%3D230810286C2A60F11EBBAA68AA230CDF40B31F31.48BC830A72D89741867F99335E2215A9FA5D5A6B%26key%3Dck2&amp;amp;iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D7f9d3fa1901972ad%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DgDaJEil3l-woMvwTF776-zijMSQ&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;ps=blogger&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/get_player&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#FFFFFF&#34; flashvars=&#34;flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D7f9d3fa1901972ad%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%253Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1399253600%26sparams%3Did,itag,source,ip,ipbits,expire%26signature%3D230810286C2A60F11EBBAA68AA230CDF40B31F31.48BC830A72D89741867F99335E2215A9FA5D5A6B%26key%3Dck2&amp;iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D7f9d3fa1901972ad%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DgDaJEil3l-woMvwTF776-zijMSQ&amp;autoplay=0&amp;ps=blogger&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;Being an infrastructure nerd, one of my favorite views was from underneath the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kiyomizudera.or.jp/lang/01.html&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kiyumizu-dera temple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;stage, which is considered earthquake-proof and is quite old. &#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px; line-height: 28px;&#34;&gt;Kiyomizu Stage was built using a special method; huge 12-meter high keyaki (Japanese Zelkova) pillars were assembled without using a single nail and the floor was installed using more than 410 cypress boards.&#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 14px; line-height: 28px;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SUmtg4-6XNc/UvQc35FqgiI/AAAAAAAAgW8/rFgm19ekAQs/s1600/20140127_143146.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SUmtg4-6XNc/UvQc35FqgiI/AAAAAAAAgW8/rFgm19ekAQs/s1600/20140127_143146.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-neXI8XWpDsU/UvQdFYOjcAI/AAAAAAAAgXE/PYgCFy06D0I/s1600/20140127_144830_Kyoto_HDR.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-neXI8XWpDsU/UvQdFYOjcAI/AAAAAAAAgXE/PYgCFy06D0I/s1600/20140127_144830_Kyoto_HDR.jpg&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;I had a relaxing ride back to Tokyo on the Shinkansen and fell asleep right away. On my last day in Japan, I took another long walk around Akiba, caught up on some email then prepped to head to Asakusa, or so I thought. I made it as far as getting tickets for the wrong line before I checked my phone and noticed that I was actually supposed to meet the #asakusarb folks in Ueno, which was in the other direction. Google Translate made it possible for me to explain to the gentleman working at the gate that I needed to exit even though I hadn&#39;t boarded a train.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;If you are in Japan and want to meet some really fun Rubyists, I highly recommend that you track down #asakusarb. They are a friendly bunch and are quite fun to spend time with even with a language barrier. They took me out for a fantastic dinner that I will never forget.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.15;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5RcFctn1gOE/UvQf7xMvBuI/AAAAAAAAgXY/tsdMisHS-OE/s1600/20140128_220640.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5RcFctn1gOE/UvQf7xMvBuI/AAAAAAAAgXY/tsdMisHS-OE/s1600/20140128_220640.jpg&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WD2bH48cUxA/UvQf87kk2QI/AAAAAAAAgXk/ZwvA_TdfoWQ/s1600/20140128_221337.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WD2bH48cUxA/UvQf87kk2QI/AAAAAAAAgXk/ZwvA_TdfoWQ/s1600/20140128_221337.jpg&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HJumubhJurE/UvQgKDtSFUI/AAAAAAAAgX4/Heniu_XpLSg/s1600/20140128_222403.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;clear: right; display: inline !important; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HJumubhJurE/UvQgKDtSFUI/AAAAAAAAgX4/Heniu_XpLSg/s1600/20140128_222403.jpg&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cwYOa-FGQZY/UvQgbooh_nI/AAAAAAAAgYM/e-K093hXXOw/s1600/20140128_223116.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cwYOa-FGQZY/UvQgbooh_nI/AAAAAAAAgYM/e-K093hXXOw/s1600/20140128_223116.jpg&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zzZO-93ldcQ/UvQgeiNy75I/AAAAAAAAgYU/q2nEfZpsOPQ/s1600/20140128_224615.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zzZO-93ldcQ/UvQgeiNy75I/AAAAAAAAgYU/q2nEfZpsOPQ/s1600/20140128_224615.jpg&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nCjsZas7SHA/UvQgWeOcTSI/AAAAAAAAgYE/T0BcV6Wp_BA/s1600/20140128_222521.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nCjsZas7SHA/UvQgWeOcTSI/AAAAAAAAgYE/T0BcV6Wp_BA/s1600/20140128_222521.jpg&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 18.399999618530273px;&#34;&gt;Everything was delicious, even/especially those things I hadn&#39;t tried before. Thank you again to the members of #asakusarb! I&#39;m sure we&#39;ll meet again.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;I puttered around in the morning, packing and getting ready for the return trip to California. I ended up taking the Narita Express from Tokyo station, which takes a little longer, but I wasn&#39;t in a rush and enjoyed the scenery. The flight from Narita to LAX was as good as a 9hr flight can be and I arrived home early to spend time with a very happy little boy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WhuKQugCJQM/UvQpHMyMJYI/AAAAAAAAgY0/xvrkJSAf9As/s1600/1559543_10152205294907375_1621044940_o.jpg&#34; imageanchor=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WhuKQugCJQM/UvQpHMyMJYI/AAAAAAAAgY0/xvrkJSAf9As/s1600/1559543_10152205294907375_1621044940_o.jpg&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;Best. Trip. Ever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&#34;&gt;-Al&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermocouples: safe &amp; silent failures</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-12-12-thermocouples-safe-silent-failures</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 23:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-12-12-thermocouples-safe-silent-failures</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Captain! The thermocouple is failing, the engines are down and we can’t start them until it’s fixed!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sounds cool, right? This humble safety device isn’t that far-fetched. If you have a gas-powered hot water heater, you have one of your very own. It solves a dangerous problem with pilot lights. A pilot light is a small flame that is kept burning indefinitely inside your gas furnace or hot water heater. It gets a tiny trickle of gas from the main supply using barely enough volume to show up on your bill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The engineers in the audience will ask, what happens when the pilot light goes out? Without a thermocouple, it will seep tiny bits of gas into the combustion chamber of the device. In a few hours, it can leak enough gas for a small explosion, probably just enough to shorten your eyebrows. If you were on vacation in Tahiti for a month and there is no circulation, enough gas could build up to some serious damage to homes and humans.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The engineering requirements are interesting:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;no external electricity is available&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;has to be reliable&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;has to work in a multitude of physical environments, from indoor closets to filthy barns&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;must behave consistently across a large temperature range&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;cannot require regular maintenance&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;HUMAN SAFETY IS AT RISK&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;When you need something reliable, you need something simple. Enter the thermocouple.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The science of how a thermocouple works is described on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermocouple&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to send that to people, but it requires a lot of background in physics to even parse what the article says. While the physics in play are fascinating, at the end of the day it’s a simple device. The trick is in the first sentence on Wikipedia,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“In 1821, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany&#34;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estonia&#34;&gt;Estonian&lt;/a&gt; physicist &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Johann_Seebeck&#34;&gt;Thomas Johann Seebeck&lt;/a&gt; discovered that when any conductor is subjected to a thermal gradient, it will generate a voltage.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What does this have to do with hot water heaters? We need a way to detect when the pilot light has gone out. No electronics, or even electricity is available. Natural gas burns at 900-1,500° Celsius. You don’t even have to convert that to Fahrenheit to see that we have a considerable temperature delta at our disposal, so there’s an opportunity to use the Seebeck effect to create a safe and reliable device.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In layman terms, the thermocouple found in household hot water heaters is a probe that is placed inside a flame with two wires made of different metal. This creates a temperature gradient, since the metals disperse heat at different rates. This generates a few microwatts of current, which is boosted by a transformer connected to a solenoid. When current is present, the solenoid holds the gas valve open. When there is not enough current, the valve is pushed closed by a spring, so most failures will lead to the gas being turned off, including the thermocouple itself failing. The device itself is intended to act like a fuse or breaker, giving up before any other component resulting in a known-safe condition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Arial; font-size: 15px; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux on ZFS</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-11-12-arch-linux-on-zfs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 22:12:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-11-12-arch-linux-on-zfs</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I&#39;m starting to work on a new talk about disk latency and decided it&#39;s time to finally get my Linux workstation up to date. I also have a nice monitor that my Mac refuses to drive properly, so I figure I&#39;ll bring the machine back as a graphical desktop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The last time I worked on this machine, I installed&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.funtoo.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Funtoo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://open-zfs.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;root using bits of the guide on the Funtoo Wiki here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://open-zfs.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34;&gt;http://open-zfs.org/wiki/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;. I changed a few things along the way. Overall, it works great. I have 4 500G drives in ZFS mirrors. I can take snapshots of the root filesystem before making changes. Creating filesystems for things like /srv/work or similar is a &#39;zfs create&#39; away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then I went to install XFCE and got to thinking about the incredible amount of time it was going to take to build the system and said, &#34;screw it install Arch.&#34; I&#39;ll talk about why I love Arch another time, for now I want to talk about how ZFS made it easy to transition to another distribution with the ability to change back any time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs create -o mountpoint=/mnt/arch tank/arch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Courier New&#39;, Courier, monospace;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs create -o compression=lzjb tank/arch/root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs create tank/arch/install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;OK, big deal. We have an empty directory on ZFS. tank/arch is for organizational purposes and matches how I have Funtoo installed in tank/funtoo. tank/arch/root will contain the root filesystem. tank/arch/install will be used for the Arch install chroot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Arch wiki has decent instructions. I won&#39;t rehash them here. I used the Arch chroot method.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Install_from_Existing_Linux&#34;&gt;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Install_from_Existing_Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The first step is to mount the new root filesystem under the installer chroot. A bind mount would work fine, but I chose to use ZFS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs set mountpoint=/mnt/arch/install/root.x86_64/mnt tank/arch/root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then continue with the install.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;wget&amp;nbsp;http://www.gtlib.gatech.edu/pub/archlinux/iso/2013.11.01/archlinux-bootstrap-2013.11.01-x86_64.tar.gz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;tar -C /mnt/arch/install -xzvf /tmp/archlinux-bootstrap-2013.11.01-x86_64.tar.gz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;bash /mnt/arch/install/root.x86_64/bin/arch-chroot /mnt/arch/install/root.x86_64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Before the arch-chroot script would work, I had to edit it and comment out the &#34;track_root shm ...&#34;. In my copy that is line 75. It looks like a bug, since it isn&#39;t really required at all for installations and it&#39;s already mounted on /dev which gets bind mounted before /dev/shm. Moving on ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;pacman-key --init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;pacman-key --populate archlinux&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I had to edit the pacstrap script the same way as the chroot script (they share the same function) to disable the check for /dev/shm. After that, it&#39;s just a normal installation of the base system. I will add other packages after a snapshot and the first boot into the new install.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;pacstrap -d /mnt base&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Something weird happens here. Pacstrap works fine. The system installs and I can look inside /mnt and see all the files I expect to see. Once I exit the chroot created by arch-chroot, it becomes invisble. After unmounting /mnt, the files are back! I don&#39;t see anything in arch-chroot that might mask the mountpoint, so I suspect something in ZFS isn&#39;t interacting with chroot the way I expect. In any case, the quick solution is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs umount /mnt/arch/install/root.x86_64/mnt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;zfs set mountpoint=/mnt/arch/root tank/arch/root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New, Courier, monospace; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;mv&amp;nbsp;/mnt/arch/install/root.x86_64/*&amp;nbsp;/mnt/arch/root&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&#39;ll chase down what&#39;s going on with the chroot for another post. I tried bind mounting and it had the same problem, which is weird when things like /dev are working fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The rest of this is pretty boring. Set up grub, etc.. It&#39;s all in the wiki so I won&#39;t cover it here unless I find something else weird.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foodfight!</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-11-06-foodfight</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 05:41:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-11-06-foodfight</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Thanks to the Foodfighters&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bryanwb&#34; style=&#34;-webkit-transition: color 0.3s; background-color: white; border: 0px; color: #751590; font-family: Georgia, &#39;Times New Roman&#39;, serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 24px; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; transition: color 0.3s; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap; word-wrap: break-word;&#34;&gt;@bryanwb&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mikefiedler&#34; style=&#34;-webkit-transition: color 0.3s; background-color: white; border: 0px; color: #751590; font-family: Georgia, &#39;Times New Roman&#39;, serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 24px; margin: 0px; padding: 0px; transition: color 0.3s; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap; word-wrap: break-word;&#34;&gt;@mikefiedler&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for having me on the show! I hope we speak again soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foodfightshow.org/2013/11/livin-on-the-edge-with-al-tobey.html&#34;&gt;http://foodfightshow.org/2013/11/livin-on-the-edge-with-al-tobey.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endurance Predation</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-10-11-endurance-predation</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 01:42:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-10-11-endurance-predation</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I started running in August. It was soon after our puppy, Rufus, got clearance from the veterinarian to go for walks in the neighborhood. We started out by going on long walks. It wasn&#39;t wearing Rufus out, so I started running short distances with him. I&#39;d be winded after 100ft, walk a while, then try again. I did that for many weeks. I took my time on purpose - my heart has 36 years of neglect to make up for, and my puppy needs to work up to it too. Rather than pushing too hard and injuring myself, I forced myself to take it easy and it has paid off. Over time, I got to the point where Rufus would fall behind during running intervals. That was satisfying. I ran two miles earlier this week.I feel awesome. That&#39;s two times further than I&#39;ve ever run before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Running is probably the smartest move I&#39;ve made in a long time. I can think faster and more clearly. I sleep better and find it easier to relax. I&#39;m down 10 pounds already with a goal to lose another 20 putting me below 200 pounds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m happy to say that I&#39;m turning into one of &#39;those people&#39;. I can go on and on about why I love my Vibram Five-Fingers shoes. I&#39;m doing my first 5k this December. I plan to do a 10k next summer, then a half marathon next winter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If anybody else is interested in running in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eventbrite.com/event/5248171422/es2/?rank=1/&#34;&gt;Santa Run&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on December 15 in San Jose, leave a comment or ping @AlTobey on Twitter.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello (again) World</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-10-07-hello-again-world</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 19:15:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2013-10-07-hello-again-world</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
One of the things that has bothered me over the last few years is that I have a strong desire to hack on open source projects and share what I&#39;ve learned. But I didn&#39;t, at least nowhere near as much as I wanted. I had plenty of excuses. It usually boiled down to family or work. I was on call all the time for years and told myself I didn&#39;t have time to write. When I wasn&#39;t working, I was trying to be a good dad and spent time with the family. Then there were the hours after bedtime when I had no excuse, but nobody can be &#34;on&#34; all the time, so while I&#39;d get the occasional burst of motivation, little progress was made.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now that I&#39;m working at Datastax as Open Source Mechanic, there are no excuses. It&#39;s literally my job to do all those things. This is my first entry of what I intend to be regular installments. My technical articles will land on Planet Cassandra while personal / rambling / &#34;behind the scenes&#34; posts will remain here for now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might ask, what is an Open Source Mechanic? My official title is actually Open Source Advocate, but it sounds too much like some kind of lawyer to my ears so I asked if I could use mechanic. A mechanic fixes things, fabricates parts when needed, and applies grease where grease is needed. That&#39;s me in a nutshell. It&#39;s in my paternal legacy going back many generations. This title makes me happy and gives me purpose when I&#39;m sitting around thinking &#34;what should I be doing right now?&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This week, I&#39;m working on VM images that contain Apache Cassandra. These images will be on USB drives we give away at conferences. They will be downloadable. When you boot the image, Cassandra will start up and allow you to interact with it immediately. My goal is to eventually have these images built &amp;amp; QA&#39;d by a righteous union of Jenkins and Packer. For now I&#39;m hand-rolling them so I can have something for Cassandra Summit EU. I have another post in progress documenting all the steps required to make a hand-rolled image. I&#39;ll do the same for the continuous integration setup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The build is going smoothly. I&#39;m primarily working in VMware Fusion on OSX and will test in VirtualBox and Qemu/KVM. I hope to have an image that works for all three. I chose to go with Arch Linux just because it&#39;s what I like right now and I get to make the call.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;m not sure what the long-term distro will be yet. I&#39;m thinking about Arch or Fedora so I can put together nice systemd integration, but there&#39;s something to be said for the popularity of certain Debian derivatives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No more excuses.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test &amp; Build Automation with btrfs</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2012-05-17-test-build-automation-with-btrfs</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 19:08:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2012-05-17-test-build-automation-with-btrfs</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article describes how to set up a system for fast testing and package builds on a single machine using btrfs snapshots and chroot. There are tools around that perform similar tasks; even if you choose one of them, I hope this is still useful in demonstrating what those tools do under the covers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve used this approach to test Puppet setups in LXC scheduled as a Jenkins job. These days, I&amp;#39;m using it to build packages for our monitoring agent with fpm (https://github.com/jordansissel/fpm). My team has to support an agent build on many Ubuntu LTS releases, 32-bit (old EC2 m1.small / c1.medium instances) and 64-bit architectures. The agent is written in Ruby - rather than trying to support mangled or ancient rubies, we&amp;#39;re bundling our own copy of Ruby 1.9.3 with all the gems in the same package.  We started with a single binary built on the lowest common denominator platform, but it wasn&amp;#39;t ideal. When building across 6 installations ([hardy, lucid, precise] x [i386, x86_64]), running VM&amp;#39;s for builds isn&amp;#39;t really efficient. Using chroots and snapshots makes building the package consistently on one box a snap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a modern 64-bit Linux installation that has a build of debootstrap&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;around 20GB of disk space&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;btrfs-progs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2&gt;System Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re sitting on Mac OSX or Windows, you should fire up VirtualBox (or VMWare / Parallels / etc.) and install your favorite modern Linux distribution.  Since I&amp;#39;m using debootstrap, using a Debian variant makes things a much easier. I&amp;#39;ve had luck building / installing debootstrap on other distros, but that&amp;#39;s a lot of work that&amp;#39;s out of scope for this article.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once Linux is installed, make sure you can sudo to root and have a chroot command available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Install Packages&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Debian / Ubuntu&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re using the newest version you want to build for, you can simply install deboostrap. Otherwise, you&amp;#39;ll probably want to install a newer package than comes with the distribution. When I went to build Ubuntu 12.04 images from 10.04, I had to compromise and pull the precise script from the debootstrap tarball.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install debootstrap&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;This worked fine on my Ubuntu Lucid VM, YMMV:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/pool/main/d/debootstrap/debootstrap_1.0.40~precise1_all.deb&lt;br /&gt;sudo dpkg -i debootstrap_1.0.40~precise1_all.deb&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Gentoo / Funtoo&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo emerge -av dev-util/debootstrap&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4&gt;CentOS (and other RPM distros, adjust to taste):&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo rpm -ivh http://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/6/x86_64/epel-release-6-5.noarch.rpm&lt;br /&gt;sudo yum install debootstrap # from EPEL&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Disk Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this section, I&amp;#39;ll describe 3 methods for setting up a volume to hold your btrfs filesystem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If your root disk is already using btrfs and you&amp;#39;re comfortable experimenting on it, you can skip head to &amp;quot;create top-level subvolumes.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;loopback&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the lowest common denominator and also consumes the least space. I would not use this in production if avoidable, but it&amp;#39;s fine for messing around.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo modprobe loop&lt;br /&gt;device=$(losetup --find)&lt;br /&gt;sudo truncate -s 20G snapfs.img&lt;br /&gt;sudo losetup $device snapfs.img&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;LVM&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Assuming you only have one volume group and maybe don&amp;#39;t know what it was named (e.g. your distro created it). Adjust to taste if you&amp;#39;re comfortable with LVM. This is what I&amp;#39;m using on my primary workstation for now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;vg=$(sudo vgdisplay |awk &amp;#39;/VG Name/{print $3}&amp;#39;)&lt;br /&gt;sudo lvcreate -L 20G -n lv_snapfs $vg&lt;br /&gt;device=&amp;quot;/dev/$vg/lv_snapfs&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Whole disks / Partitions&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m developing inside a VM, I often create an additional virtual disk to do things like this. Most of the GUI-ridden hypervisors will walk you through this. On a production system, it would be awful nice to use a fast RAID. In EC2, this would apply well to any of the non-root drive options like ephemeral disks or EBS volumes.  The simplest, though not totally correct approach, is to mkfs the whole drive. This is how I&amp;#39;ve configured my VM on my machine at home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;drive=&amp;quot;/dev/sdc&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;device=&amp;quot;${drive}1&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;sudo sgdisk -Z $drive  # wipe any existing partition tables&lt;br /&gt;sudo sgdisk -og $drive # create a new GPT label&lt;br /&gt;sudo sgdisk -n 1:2048:0 -c 1:snapfs -t 1:8300 $drive # create one partition using the whole drive&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Create &amp;amp; Mount btrfs Filesystem&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# where $drive is set by one of the commands above&lt;br /&gt;sudo mkfs.btrfs -L snapfs $drive&lt;br /&gt;sudo mkdir /snapfs&lt;br /&gt;sudo mount $drive /snapfs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Create Top-level Subvolumes&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;These don&amp;#39;t necessarily have to be subvolumes, but it seems like the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume create /snapfs/roots&lt;br /&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume create /snapfs/snapshots&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Create OS Roots&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now create your OS roots using debootstrap. febootstrap usage is probably similar but I haven&amp;#39;t tried it. We&amp;#39;re only going to do this once and use snapshots to effectively cache the OS root with fast copies. If you&amp;#39;re messing around with this a lot, you might want to use a simple caching proxy to reduce bandwidth and speed up further downloads of the same packages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume create /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64&lt;br /&gt;sudo debootstrap --variant=buildd --arch x86_64 precise /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The sources.list installed by debootstrap only contains main. Before moving on, it&amp;#39;s best to update it. Sometimes I&amp;#39;ll take a snapshot before this step, but I feel that outdated images are not that useful. If your configuration managemen tools know how to configure roots other than /, you probably want to use whatever apt recipes you have for that instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat &amp;gt; /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF&lt;br /&gt;deb http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/ precise main restricted universe multiverse&lt;br /&gt;deb http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/ precise-updates main restricted universe multiverse&lt;br /&gt;deb http://security.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/ precise-security main restricted universe multiverse&lt;br /&gt;EOF&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 apt-get update&lt;br /&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 apt-get dist-upgrade&lt;br /&gt;# needed for simple scripting&lt;br /&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 apt-get install apt-utils lsb-release curl wget&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Take a Snapshot&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Right after creating the root, I usually take a snapshot in case I make a mistake later on. Snapshots aren&amp;#39;t really different from subvolumes in treatment, so they&amp;#39;re trivial to snapshot again back to /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 if it gets messed up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume snapshot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 /snapfs/snapshots/ubuntu-precise-amd64-debootstrap&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Add Packages to Taste&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now is when you install your configuration management system and let it take over for a bit. It&amp;#39;s also a good time to consider switching to nslite&amp;#39;s nschroot or LXC to containerize its run so it can&amp;#39;t affect as much of your host system. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Puppet&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is minimal. You might want to follow their instructions and import the puppet key. Obviously you&amp;#39;ll want to import your puppet config, etc. as necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;deb http://apt.puppetlabs.com/ubuntu precise main&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64/etc/apt/sources.list.d/puppetlabs.list&lt;br /&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 apt-get install puppet-common puppet facter openssl&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Building Ruby Packages&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debian and Ubuntu modify their Ruby packages and make them pretty difficult to use in some ways. They&amp;#39;re also usually quite a ways behind current resulting in wide-spread use of tools like RVM and rbenv. Both of those tools tend to promote the practice of building machine code on edge machines, which some of us neckbeards think is a pretty bad idea. My preferred workaround is to build Ruby into packages that install into /opt/ruby/$version and are accessed by setting PATH, rbenv, or shebang modification.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I prefer to set up most of the build environment in the &amp;quot;root&amp;quot; to save time and bandwidth on each build.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 apt-get install build-essential gpgv libssl-dev zlib1g-dev git-core uuid-dev libreadline-dev pkg-config libffi-dev&lt;br /&gt;cd /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64/tmp&lt;br /&gt;git clone https://github.com/sstephenson/ruby-build.git&lt;br /&gt;cd ruby-build&lt;br /&gt;sudo bash install.sh&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then, each time I build Ruby, I create a snapshot of the root so I can destroy it and any pollution afterwards.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 /usr/local/bin/ruby-build 1.9.3-p194 /opt/ruby/1.9.3-p194&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Building 32-bit Binaries From 64-bit Systems&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;util-linux has a utility called &amp;quot;setarch&amp;quot; that&amp;#39;s really handy for building 32-bit binaries. True cross-build is a bit trickier, whereas setarch and its linux32 alias are quite easy and reliable. Simply prefix your commands with &amp;quot;linux32&amp;quot; and the environment will be mangled enough to trick most scripts into thinking they&amp;#39;re running on i386 systems.  The Ruby configure script builds a cleaner RbConfig with this setup; other packages (like openssl) get totally confused without it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume create /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-i386&lt;br /&gt;sudo debootstrap --variant=buildd --arch i386 precise /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-i386 http://archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/&lt;br /&gt;# repeate further setup as above ... but prefix chroot as below if you like (it&amp;#39;s not really necessary until you get to the builds)&lt;br /&gt;sudo linux32 --uname-2.6 chroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-i386 /usr/local/bin/ruby-build 1.9.3-p194 /opt/ruby/1.9.3-p194&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;nschroot&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;nschroot is a tiny utility I created to get most of the benefits of containers without all of LXC&amp;#39;s statefulness and complexity. It&amp;#39;s simple enough to build, just get the code from github (https://github.com/tobert/nslite) and run make. Then simply use &amp;quot;nschroot&amp;quot; instead of plain chroot and the new processes will run in a namespace.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nschroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 /bin/bash&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; mount none /proc -t proc&lt;br /&gt;&amp;gt; ps -ef&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many applications don&amp;#39;t need proc or sys so you don&amp;#39;t need to mount them. Another simple trick is to write a shell script into the root and use it as init, just like in initramfs (a.k.a. initrd).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat &amp;gt; init.sh &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF&lt;br /&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;br /&gt;mount none /proc -t proc&lt;br /&gt;mount none /sys -t sysfs&lt;br /&gt;mount none /tmp -t tmpfs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# run some stuff&lt;br /&gt;puppet --verbose --debug /etc/puppet/manifests/site.pp&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# kill everything but $$, be really careful testing this!&lt;br /&gt;for pid in $(ps -eo pid)&lt;br /&gt;do&lt;br /&gt;  if [ $pid -ne $$ -a -d /proc/$pid ] ; then&lt;br /&gt;    kill -9 $pid&lt;br /&gt;  fi&lt;br /&gt;done&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;umount /proc&lt;br /&gt;umount /sys&lt;br /&gt;umount /tmp&lt;br /&gt;EOF&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;sudo cp init.sh /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64/init.sh&lt;br /&gt;sudo nschroot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 /bin/bash /init.sh&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Testing With LXC&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;LXC is a set of tools on top of facilities that are standard in modern Linux kernels. Cgroups provides a solid resource limiting and tracking system, namespaces provide containers with private pids, ipc, and the like. It also hooks up capabilities to decrease security exposure. Many distributions require modification to run fully in LXC. There&amp;#39;s also the lxc-exec option to run a single process in the container, but that requires lxc-exec inside the container.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t tested this bit in a while. Here&amp;#39;s most of what was in my old scripts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;now=$(date +%s)&lt;br /&gt;snapshot=&amp;quot;/snapfs/snapshots/ubuntu-precise-amd64-test-${now}&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;sudo btrfs subvolume snapshot /snapfs/roots/ubuntu-precise-amd64 $snapshot&lt;br /&gt;sudo chroot $snapshot apt-get install lxc&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;cat &amp;gt; test-$now.conf &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF&lt;br /&gt;lxc.utsname = puppet-test-${now}&lt;br /&gt;lxc.rootfs = $snapshot&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.cpuset.cpus = 0,1&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.cpu.shares = 100&lt;br /&gt;lxc.mount.entry=none proc    proc   nodev,noexec,nosuid 0 0&lt;br /&gt;lxc.mount.entry=none dev/shm tmpfs  defaults 0 0&lt;br /&gt;lxc.mount.entry=none dev/pts devpts defaults 0 0&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.deny = a&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 1:3 rw  # null&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 1:5 rw  # zero&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 1:8 rwm # urandom&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 1:9 rwm # random&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 4:0 rwm # tty0&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 4:1 rwm # tty1&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 5:0 rwm # tty&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 5:1 rwm # console&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 5:2 rwm # pts/ptmx&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cgroup.devices.allow = c 136:* rwm # pts/*&lt;br /&gt;lxc.cap.drop = sys_boot sys_module sys_time&lt;br /&gt;EOF&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# install puppet / chef / cfengine / whatever&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# if serverless, push your config code in&lt;br /&gt;# if using a server, you probably want to copy pre-cached ssl/cfengine keys in to avoid&lt;br /&gt;# spamming the server with ephemeral test keys&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# e.g. puppet masterless&lt;br /&gt;sudo lxc-execute -f test-$now.conf -n puppet-test-$now -- puppet --verbose --debug /etc/puppet/manifests/site.pp&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Other Approaches&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started out using all this stuff with Funtoo root &amp; child filesystems. With a little rpath and other linker tinkering you can use Funtoo/Gentoo to build packages with totally self-contained libc and everything.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a number of other ways to do this. It looks like Debian uses dchroot / schroot to do almost exactly the same thing in their build system.  This is the low-level way to do it and does not require much more than the standard OS tools + btrfsprogs once the initial setup is complete.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With a little adjustment, a similar procedure will work with ZFS (http://zfsonlinux.org/) or even LVM snapshots (but those can be slow).  I&amp;#39;ve even used git branches to do the same thing, but they get slow quite quickly with the amount of data required.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At some point, I might give multistrap (http://wiki.debian.org/Multistrap) a try.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have experimented with using unionfs. This works great for testing in chroots and LXC on normal filesystems. Another advantage is that you can inspect the COW area to see the files and content that changed relative to the source image. Accounting and managing mounts is more tedious, but for some people it may be a superior base to build on.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.debian.org/Debootstrap&#34;&gt;http://wiki.debian.org/Debootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/DebootstrapChroot&#34;&gt;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/DebootstrapChroot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=article&amp;amp;item=btrfs_lzo_2638&#34;&gt;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=article&amp;amp;item=btrfs_lzo_2638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Experiment Language Choices</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2011-07-21-new-experiment-language-choices</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 06:13:25 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2011-07-21-new-experiment-language-choices</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
(edit: I&#39;m still tinkering with the ideas and have started learning Go, but will probably end up doing this project in either python or bash) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;My evolving side project is a configuration management suite that:&lt;pre&gt;1.) uses as much of git as possible and sensible&lt;br /&gt;2.) lightweight&lt;br /&gt;3.) simple things must be very fast turnaround to/from thought&lt;-&gt;production&lt;br /&gt;4.) all configs (and binaries if you like) versioned bit-for-bit for all time&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ll write more about the overall system design later; I&#39;ve written a bit of an intro and will post it when I have code to present (here&#39;s what I have in mind for fs permissions: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/1096381&#34;&gt;gist&lt;/a&gt;) I&#39;m implementing some tools now that I&#39;ve got the branching &amp; config strategy worked out. I could whip out a lot of it in Perl pretty handily, but I suspect it&#39;ll be a one-man show forever if I go that route. At work, almost everything is done in Ruby, which I still don&#39;t really like much. Plus two of the leading CFM tools are already in Ruby, so I feel like it&#39;s time for something different. So, here&#39;s what I&#39;m considering and why:&lt;pre&gt;1) Go&lt;br /&gt;  +) generates regular binaries, no VM to maintain on nodes&lt;br /&gt;  +) good C compatibility, already has libgit2 bindings&lt;br /&gt;  +) garbage collected, first-class strings&lt;br /&gt;  +) (yes, +) DNA from C, Erlang, Plan9, and Inferno/Limbo&lt;br /&gt;     e.g.) lightweight processes, channels, goroutines&lt;br /&gt;  -) I&#39;d have to learn from scratch&lt;br /&gt;  -) AFAIK nobody on my team knows/uses it (obscure)&lt;br /&gt;2) C&lt;br /&gt;  +) compiled, works literally everywhere, knows your mom intimately&lt;br /&gt;  +) good match with git, openssl/gnutls, and libgit2&lt;br /&gt;  +) igraph looks neat for smart path &amp; network&lt;br /&gt;  -) manual memory, thread, and process management :(&lt;br /&gt;  -) I&#39;m rusty as the Titanic&lt;br /&gt;3) Perl &gt;=5.8&lt;br /&gt;  +) installed everywhere&lt;br /&gt;  +) I&#39;m good/fast at it, prototype in a couple weeks&lt;br /&gt;  +) many git utilities are written in perl, good match&lt;br /&gt;  -) declining popularity, fractured community&lt;br /&gt;  -) modern libs require too much baggage (e.g. Moose)&lt;br /&gt;  -) XS is the devil, no usable libgit2 bindings&lt;br /&gt;4) Python&lt;br /&gt;  +) installed everywhere I care about&lt;br /&gt;  +) thriving community&lt;br /&gt;  +) I have some experience (though still much slower than perl)&lt;br /&gt;  +) libgit2 bindings exist&lt;br /&gt;  +) some of the git tools are already python&lt;br /&gt;  -) difficult to bundle with zero dependencies outside the git branch&lt;br /&gt;  -) v2.5 -&gt; v3.x transition is in progress, which to choose? (prob 2.7)&lt;br /&gt;5) Java&lt;br /&gt;  +) just kidding!&lt;br /&gt;6) Javascript/NodeJS&lt;br /&gt;  -) I&#39;m not kidding&lt;br /&gt;  +) garbage collected, closures, functional style available, naturally async&lt;br /&gt;  +) growing popularity, modules I&#39;d need are fairly mature (relative to node.js)&lt;br /&gt;  -) rapidly changing ecosystem/interfaces&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To be honest, I&#39;m really leaning towards Go right now but it&#39;d add a month or so before I have something useful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Comments, suggestions? Don&#39;t hold back, you know I wouldn&#39;t ;)
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over-breeding &amp; Culling EC2 Instances for IO Performance</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2011-09-21-over-breeding-culling-ec2-instances-for</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 06:06:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2011-09-21-over-breeding-culling-ec2-instances-for</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I&#39;ve heard other people talk about this on Twitter or at conferences, but as far as I can remember, nobody has described the nuts and bolts of finding tolerable-performance ephemeral disks in EC2.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently spun up a 12-node Cassandra cluster in EC2 and, since it&#39;s a database, I decided to do some basic tire-kicking and learned a few things along the way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rule: always zero your ephemerals if you care about performance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why: Amazon is likely using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_file&#34;&gt;sparse files&lt;/a&gt; to back ephemerals (and probably EBS, I have no experience there). This makes perfect sense, because: &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;you get free thin provisioning, so unused disk doesn&#39;t go to waste&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Xen supports it well&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;it&#39;s easy to manage lots &amp; lots of them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;it&#39;s trivial to export over all common network block protocols (e.g. AoE, iSCSI) &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Because there is an extra step of allocating a backing block for a sparse file for every block in your VM, performance will be all over the map while zeroing the disks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Script #1:&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/1231302.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I usually launch my zeroing script with &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: monospace;&#34;&gt;cl-run.pl --list burnin -s zero-drives.sh&lt;/span&gt;. The &#34;burnin&#34; list is just all the ec2 hostnames, one per line, in ~/.dsh/machines.burnin. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Culling round 1&lt;/b&gt;: Look at the raw throughput of all of the nodes and cull anything that looks abnormally low. For example, when building the aforementioned cluster, I kept getting really obviously bad instances in one of the us-east-1 AZ&#39;s.  This is what I saw when using my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tobert/perl-ssh-tools/blob/master/cl-netstat.pl&#34;&gt;cluster netstat&lt;/a&gt; tool for a batch of m1.xlarge&#39;s in us-east-1c.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/1215444.js&#34;&gt; &lt;/script&gt; I immediately culled off everything doing under 10k IOPS for more than a minute. If you examine the per-disk stats with &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: monospace;&#34;&gt;iostat -x 2&lt;/span&gt;, you&#39;ll usually see one disk with insanely high (&gt;1000ms) latency all the time. There are certainly false-negatives at this phase, but I don&#39;t really care since instances are cheap and time is not. I ended up starting around 30 instances in that one troublesome AZ to find 3 with sustainable IOPS in the most trivial of tests (dd). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;When I think I have enough obviously tolerable nodes for a race, I kick off another zero round. Once the load levels out a  little, I take a snapshot I like of the cl-netstat.pl output and process it in a hacky way to sort by IOPS and add which EC2 zone the instance is in and its instance ID so I can kill the losers without digging around.  Here&#39;s an example from a round of testing I did for a recent MySQL cluster deployment: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/1231333.js&#34;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I picked the top few instances from each AZ and terminated the rest. Job done. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is a pretty crude process in many ways. It&#39;s very manual, it requires a lot of human judgement, and most importantly, dd if=/dev/zero not a good measure of real-world performance. This process is just barely good enough to cull the worst offenders in EC2, which seem to be quite common in my recent experience. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the future, I will likely automate most of this burn-in process and add some real-world I/O generation, probably using real data. 
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Christmas Wish</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-12-23-my-christmas-wish</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 21:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-12-23-my-christmas-wish</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I wrote this email to my (non-technical) family with the subject, &#34;My Christmas Wish.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Folks,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In light of the most recent &#34;Zero Day&#34; security vulnerability in Internet Explorer, I am writing this to ask all of you who still use it to consider switching browsers.   IE is by far the most ubiquitous source of junk on Windows computers outside of unsafe downloads.   Other browsers do much more to protect you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So-called &#34;Zero Day&#34; exploits occur on a regular basis and leave you vulnerable to attack for weeks at a time.   For example, the Chinese attacks on Google relied on vulnerabilities in Internet Explorer to steal users&#39; account information. Google now has a policy tightly restricting the use of Windows and IE to only employees who need it for testing purposes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You don&#39;t have to do much to pick up malware via websites.   There are myriad ways for attackers to deliver malicious code that you will never see, and often your virus scanners cannot detect either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;http://isc.sans.edu/diary.html?storyid=10132&lt;br /&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/2488013.mspx&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s incredibly easy to avoid the whole mess.   Install another, faster and more secure browser.   Delete the IE icon from your desktop and quickstart bars, especially if others use your computer.   Set the other browser of your choice as the default.   Here&#39;s a list of modern, secure browsers, in my personal order of preference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;http://www.google.com/chrome&lt;br /&gt;http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/&lt;br /&gt;http://www.opera.com/&lt;br /&gt;http://www.apple.com/safari/&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you can&#39;t see yourself using another browser, at least use Chrome for your sensitive data and IE for everything else.  That way at least your bank accounts and health records will be slightly harder for attackers to steal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, if you haven&#39;t done it in a while, check for updates on the other programs you use regularly, especially instant messaging like Skype, AOL, MSN, and Yahoo!.  Many programs have an automatic update feature under the &#34;Help&#34; menu that will automatically do all the dirty work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Al
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride Report 2010-09-05</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-09-06-ride-report-2010-09-05</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 04:49:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-09-06-ride-report-2010-09-05</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I recently started commuting to work on my bicycle.  I recently hit 230lbs., which I&#39;ve always kept in my head as my maximum weight I&#39;ll let myself get to.   The weight problem leaves me with a conundrum.   I love eating and I hate exercising.   Fortunately, I&#39;ve always enjoyed bicycling, so the answer was to start converting my &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.org/my-29er.html&#34;&gt;2009 Marin Alpine Trail 29er&lt;/a&gt; to a commuter and combine exercise with my commute.  Riding a bicycle to work only takes me an extra 15 minutes if traffic is bad, giving me 1.5hrs of exercise every day with only a half hour added to my commute.  That&#39;s not mentioning the reduced road rage, gas, mileage on my car, and starting my day energized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ve ridden into work about 10 times now.  It&#39;s about 10 miles each way depending on my route, which I think is in the sweet spot of, &#34;far enough to make it worth getting smelly and still under an hour commute.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Meridian+Ave&amp;daddr=37.300342,-121.9135947+to:37.3107,-121.92165+to:37.311608,-121.9232834+to:37.322052,-121.9238063+to:37.33122,-121.92076+to:37.3377005,-121.943437+to:37.36394,-121.96795+to:95054&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FWgROQIdlr-7-A%3BFXYoOQIdBr-7-ClTd2wuuzSOgDHBio701dsO9A%3BFexQOQIdjp-7-CmP_p0rS8uPgDF-DNswOZP5XA%3BFXhUOQIdLZm7-CkVioyMSsuPgDGT8ytqG8JCtg%3BFUR9OQIdIpe7-CkNEdecR8uPgDHxEGNKA-a24w%3BFRShOQIdCKO7-CmVRZNsasuPgDGoCIx3E1eUoA%3BFWS6OQIdc0q7-Ck1-hXjA8uPgDHUN8tQZo7U5Q%3BFeQgOgIdsuq6-Cm5cKfZPMqPgDFaCfMd44GpTQ%3BFUyoOgIdqvi6-CkTK0sevsmPgDG3IwGPFlVbjQ&amp;mra=dvme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=5&amp;sz=14&amp;via=1,2,3,4,5,6,7&amp;dirflg=b&amp;sll=37.326762,-121.935368&amp;sspn=0.055557,0.132093&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=37.333723,-121.936226&amp;spn=0.055552,0.132093&amp;t=h&amp;z=14&amp;lci=bike&#34;&gt;Latest Work Route&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since tomorrow is a holiday and I wanted to check out some panniers at REI, I decided to ride so I could keep my body guessing.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=meridian+avenue+at+hamilton&amp;daddr=Hamilton+Ave+to:Leigh+Ave+to:37.287916,-121.945324+to:400+El+Paseo+De+Saratoga,+San+Jose,+CA+95130+(REI+-+Recreational+Equipment+Inc.)+to:Unknown+road+to:Los+Gatos+Creek+Trail&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FWwROQIdAr-7-CnRLypMvTSOgDHTkP0okSSR2A%3BFS0ROQIdoaK7-A%3BFe4jOQIdkZu7-A%3B%3BFcr7OAId8Yy6-CHxPiCxtFKs_w%3BFS_sOAIdkle7-A%3BFZ17OAIdSgK7-A&amp;mra=dvme&amp;mrcr=0&amp;mrsp=3&amp;sz=14&amp;via=1,2,3,5&amp;dirflg=b&amp;sll=37.281292,-121.958199&amp;sspn=0.055591,0.132093&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;z=14&amp;lci=bike&#34;&gt;Route&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The ride went fine and I felt pretty good the whole time.  It was really nice to be able to wear my camelback (Costco version) and stay hydrated without dinking with a water bottle.   I picked up some new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rei.com/product/768219&#34;&gt;grips&lt;/a&gt; and a pack of shot bloks.  I looked at the Ortlieb panniers which look very nice, but are way too expensive for my current level of commitment.   The laptop bag alone was something like $150.   I might go after one later after I&#39;ve totally adapted to bicycle commuting, but I&#39;m not spending $300 on bags until I&#39;m sure I&#39;ll use them for a 1000+ miles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Defeated, I rode home and browsed around the web looking at what people are doing with custom mods.    There&#39;s some really creative stuff out there, most interestingly, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Ammo-boxes-for-Panniers/step5/Load-them-up/&#34;&gt;plastic ammo cans&lt;/a&gt;.   I drove over to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scsurplus.com/&#34;&gt;Stevens Creek Surplus&lt;/a&gt;, but all they had were the classic steel cans (though they had an awesome camping section).  On the way home I thought I&#39;d stop at Home Depot and see if they had anything interesting.    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ProductDisplay?storeId=10051&amp;productId=202017995&amp;langId=-1&amp;catalogId=10053&amp;ci_sku=202017995&#34;&gt;They did.&lt;/a&gt;  I bought two &#34;Husky 16 in. Hang-Up Tool Bag&#34;, some velcro straps, and a two packs of&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.homedepot.com/h_d1/N-5yc1vZ1xgl/R-202017297/h_d2/ProductDisplay?langId=-1&amp;storeId=10051&amp;catalogId=10053&#34;&gt; flat bungee cords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tomorrow, I&#39;ll figure out how to mount the bags to my satisfaction, or return them and go for the plain &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcmelectronics.com/product/22-11100&amp;CAWELAID=462137762&#34;&gt;aluminum briefcase&lt;/a&gt; (can&#39;t find HD link).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, I&#39;m off to google some ideas for pannier hooks.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blocking SSH Attacks</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-08-12-blocking-ssh-attacks</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 19:12:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2010-08-12-blocking-ssh-attacks</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I run this on almost any server that isn&#39;t behind another firewall blocking $SSH_PORT.   I got this from somewhere else, but it was a long time ago and I don&#39;t remember the source anymore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SSH_PORT=22  # I think ssh on !22 is silly, but to each their own&lt;br /&gt;TRUSTED_SUBNET_OR_HOST=mybox.homeip.com # or a subnet you trust&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;iptables -A ssh_drop -j DROP -m comment --comment &#34;SSH attack drop&#34;&lt;br /&gt;iptables -A INPUT  -p tcp -m tcp -s $TRUSTED_SUBNET_OR_HOST --dport $SSH_PORT  -m state --state NEW -j ACCEPT&lt;br /&gt;iptables -A INPUT -p tcp -m state --state NEW --dport $SSH_PORT -m recent --name sshattack --set&lt;br /&gt;iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport $SSH_PORT -m state --state NEW -m recent --name sshattack --rcheck --seconds 60 --hitcount 3 -j LOG --log-prefix &#39;SSH Attack DROP: &#39;&lt;br /&gt;iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport $SSH_PORT -m state --state NEW -m recent --name sshattack --rcheck --seconds 60 --hitcount 3 -j ssh_drop&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Basically, this counts connection attempts on port 22 and starts dropping attempts after the third one (obviously adjust --hitcount to taste).   It times out after 60 seconds, so I don&#39;t accidentally lock myself out.    I see a few attacks a day start then go away after the drop.  I&#39;ve never seen one come back after the window reopens (unless it was myself trying to &#34;attack&#34;).  It&#39;s also 0 maintenance unlike the userspace solutions.   A lot of people like tcp wrappers, but that still lets attackers hammer the port.   Using both works nicely.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This and DenyHosts don&#39;t help with distributed attacks, which is why I&#39;m moving towards key-only logins and maybe picking up some YubiKeys. (yubico.com)
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Madness</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2008-04-06-virtualization-madness</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 18:50:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2008-04-06-virtualization-madness</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I now have all of my hardware for the virtualization project I&#39;ve been working on and have been doing final testing and setup configuration lately.  I&#39;ve had the awesome opportunity to really torture the VM setup on a test cluster in the lab.   I started out with testing storage solutions on a 10x10 (physical x virtual) cluster of Dell 1950&#39;s with 8GB of RAM and two Core 2 Duo&#39;s.   I still have the demo NetApp 3070 that proved out NFS storage for VM images, and now I have all of the upgrades in the 1950&#39;s to push them to 32GB of RAM and hardware RAID controllers.    I&#39;ve learned quite a bit in the process of all of this testing and thought I&#39;d share some tips here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of the VM&#39;s I&#39;ll be running in production will come from a P2V migration, but because my predecessors were smart enough to concentrate all of our custom content under a single mountpoint,   most of the systems can be migrated to new OS images (and thus upgrade ancient OS&#39;s in the process).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Tip #1&lt;/span&gt;: when building servers (physical or virtual), ignore the &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Filesystem_Hierarchy_Standard&#34;&gt;FHS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for your local content.  The common place these days is /srv, so put anything that does not come in a distribution package here. Backups are as easy as &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;tar -czvf /someplace/`hostname -s`-srv.tar.gz /srv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;.  Migrations and cluster scaleouts similarly easy: &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;rsync -ave ssh /srv/./ username@newbox:/srv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;.   When a package really wants you to conform to FHS, work around it with symlinks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Edit:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;it was pointed out to me that FHS actually recommends /srv.  To be honest, I haven&#39;t looked at it in years.    In any case, my point remains valid, since most distros interpret FHS in their own way and still put things like web content and database files under /var.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ok, so that wasn&#39;t so much about virtualization.   A somewhat little known fact is that almost all of the virtualization players out there, be it Xen, KVM, VMWare, or even Microsoft, is that the VM&#39;s themselves are not actually that hard to migrate between them.   You only have to figure it out once then, especially for Linux VM&#39;s, you can script it and do them in bulk.   Probably the two most valuable tools for this are kpartx and qemu-img.    Xen doesn&#39;t seem to install qemu-img with its Qemu stuff, but it&#39;s well-worth keeping around on your dom0&#39;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Tip #2&lt;/span&gt;: learn to use kpartx and qemu-img, even if you&#39;re using LVM or individual LUN&#39;s for your VM&#39;s.    qemu-img can read and write raw, vmdisk, qcow2, and a few other formats and is pretty deft at enabling &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparse_file&#34;&gt;sparse file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; support, which is pretty nifty.   For instance, if you download a VMWare appliance and want to run it under Xen, it&#39;s trivial to convert to a raw image with &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;qemu-img convert vmappliance.img -O raw vmappliance-raw.img&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;.    kpartx is nice because it will map out partitions within an image or LVM volume using device mapper.    So once that image is created, do &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;kpartx -va vmappliance-raw.img&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34; then you can mount the partitions without messing around with weird offset options to losetup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the problems I&#39;ve run into quite a lot over the last couple years&#39; of playing with Xen &amp;amp; co. is that most initramfs scripts output far too fragile and stupid environments.     With the availability of busybox and gobs of RAM these days, there is absolutely no reason I should have to screw around for hours rebooting a box because these filesystems are not smart enough to drop into a debug shell when things go wrong.     I have published a simplistic script that I occasionally use to build initrd&#39;s at &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.org/unix/index.html&#34;&gt;http://tobert.org/unix/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.   But often, for support reasons, it&#39;s not practical to run a custom generation script.   With the 2.6 Linux kernel, it&#39;s actually way easier to edit these buggers than it was back in the day, since now they&#39;re simply compressed cpio archives.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Tip #3&lt;/span&gt;: learn how to hack initrd&#39;s and get those years of your life back.   Here&#39;s how to tear it apart: &lt;pre style=&#34;font-family: courier new; font-size: 85%;&#34;&gt;mkdir /tmp/initrd&lt;br /&gt;cd /tmp/initrd&lt;br /&gt;gunzip -c /boot/initrd-`uname -r`.img |cpio -ivdm&lt;/pre&gt;The first thing to look at is the &#34;init&#34; script.   For instance, when CLVM locking is stopping you from getting to single-user, simply crack that file open and comment out all the LVM initialization code.    It&#39;s mostly a simple shell script.   Another trick is to copy busybox into the bin directory, symlink lash, then add a &#34;/bin/lash -i&#34; to the init script right before root gets mounted.    To put everything together again, you have to use the &#34;newc&#34; cpio format, so the command is (from the top of the initrd):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;font-family: courier new; font-size: 85%;&#34;&gt;find . |cpio -oH newc |gzip -c &gt; /boot/initrd-`uname -r`.img&lt;/pre&gt; To save yourself a lot of frustration, I highly recommend playing around with initramfs hacking in VM&#39;s first, since the hack/reboot/fail/reboot/hack/reboot cycle is so much faster.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Xen is pretty neat and it&#39;s nice how it&#39;s integrated with EL5 so I can just use yum to keep up to date.   While I&#39;m deploying Xen for my production stuff in the coming weeks, I&#39;m watching closely for KVM to reach a level of maturity where I can start migrating over to it.   I expect this to happen this year, but I won&#39;t go anywhere near it for production until it starts surviving my torture tests (another post, another day).  For some more eloquent writing about why KVM can be better, check out &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://udrepper.livejournal.com/&#34;&gt;Ulrich Drepper&#39;s LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, specifically &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://udrepper.livejournal.com/15795.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://udrepper.livejournal.com/17577.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.   So, what can you do to keep your VM&#39;s easy to migrate when something better comes along?   Tip #1 takes you a long ways, since even if you have to reinstall the OS, it&#39;s a pretty trivial operation (especially if you use &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cobbler.et.redhat.com/&#34;&gt;Cobbler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Tip #4&lt;/span&gt;: don&#39;t tie your VM&#39;s too tightly to one solution.    Obviously, the first step is to use &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;libvirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; rather than XenAPI.   Once I figured out all of the bits &amp;amp; pieces, it only took about an hour - mostly waiting for the damned computers - to get all my test VM&#39;s converted from Xen to KVM paravirt.    kpartx was invaluable since it let me mount the VM filesystems from the host.   All of my VM&#39;s are on NetApp NFS, so a simple shell loop made quick work of mounting all 100 filesystems in my test cluster.&lt;pre style=&#34;font-family: courier new; font-size: 85%;&#34;&gt;cd /net/vm-disks&lt;br /&gt;for vmdisk in *.img&lt;br /&gt;do&lt;br /&gt; mkdir -p /mnt/$vmdisk&lt;br /&gt; # run kpartx and grab partition #1 all at once&lt;br /&gt; DEVICE=`kpartx -v -a /net/vm-disks/$vmdisk |head -n 1 \&lt;br /&gt;          |awk &#39;{print $3}&#39;`&lt;br /&gt; mount /dev/mapper/$DEV /mnt/$vmdisk&lt;br /&gt;done&lt;/pre&gt;Once they&#39;re all mounted, it&#39;s pretty easy to loop through all of them and make a change, such as copy in a new /etc/modprobe.conf or an updated initramfs with virtio network/block drivers.  I&#39;m especially excited about KVM virtio-net with NFS root, since virtio-net is shaping up to be quite a bit faster than xennet.&lt;pre style=&#34;font-family: courier new; font-size: 85%;&#34;&gt;# install a normal kernel&lt;br /&gt;cd /mnt&lt;br /&gt;for vmdisk in *.img&lt;br /&gt;do&lt;br /&gt; chroot /mnt/$vmdisk yum -y install kernel&lt;br /&gt;done&lt;br /&gt;# and so on ...&lt;/pre&gt;You might even get away with some of these tricks on Windows VM&#39;s using ntfstools and ntfs-3g.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;Tip #5&lt;/span&gt;: when searching for best practices and tuning information, there is a lot of excellent documentation available for us Xen and KVM users in the form of VMWare documentation.  For example, I&#39;ve had really good luck with reading NetApp&#39;s docs for NetApp + VMWare (the block alignment and Oracle RAC on NFS docs are particularly good).    When vendors say &#34;we really don&#39;t do much with Xen,&#34; I ask them for VMWare whitepapers instead.    Most of the concepts are the same regardless of the hypervisor, so learn both sets of terminology and make the best of all the great documentation out there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As always, remember to make backups ...
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About @AlTobey</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/about</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/about</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AlTobey&#34;&gt;@AlTobey&lt;/a&gt; is a father, technologist, musician, and open source mechanic working for Datastax. While attending university as a music major, Al got into MUDs, C, and Linux, eventually ending up with a career as a sysadmin. Over the last 15 years, Al has worked on everything from kernel drivers to CSS, mostly from inside operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License and Credits</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/attributes</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/attributes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AlTobey&#34;
           class=&#34;twitter-follow-button&#34;
           data-link-color=&#34;#0069D6&#34;
           data-show-count=&#34;false&#34;&gt;@AlTobey&lt;/a&gt;
with &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugo.spf13.com/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; property=&#34;dct:title&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/span&gt;
by
&lt;span xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34;&gt;Al Tobey&lt;/span&gt;
is licensed under a
&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacting @AlTobey</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/contact</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/contact</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/AlTobey&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;icon&#34; src=&#34;/images/twitter_mini-a.png&#34; alt=&#34;Follow AlTobey on Twitter&#34;/&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smedia&#34;&gt;Twitter: @AlTobey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tobert@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;icon&#34; src=&#34;/images/brakyell-50x50.jpg&#34; width=&#34;16&#34; height=&#34;16&#34;/&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smedia&#34;&gt;tobert@gmail.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pub/al-tobey/3/5b8/600&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;icon&#34; src=&#34;/images/linkedin_12x12.gif&#34; width=&#34;16&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smedia&#34;&gt;LinkedIn: Al Tobey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/people/Albert-Tobey/100001506241937&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;icon&#34; src=&#34;/images/eIpbnVKI9lR.png&#34; width=&#34;16&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; alt=&#34;Facebook&#34; /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smedia&#34;&gt;Facebook: Albert Tobey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tobert&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;icon&#34; src=&#34;/images/github.png&#34; alt=&#34;Github&#34;/&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;smedia&#34;&gt;Github: tobert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>@AlTobey Writes</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit. Illum ex deleniti ut tenetur amet accusantium dolores nam provident! Ipsum, dicta voluptatum quas architecto nostrum sapiente eos commodi numquam accusantium reprehenderit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doloremque, veritatis qui impedit expedita quas distinctio temporibus repellendus dicta debitis iure molestias recusandae cum facere natus esse saepe inventore beatae ipsum soluta voluptas in quaerat nam culpa id autem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sequi eum impedit distinctio facilis repudiandae provident iure illo quia autem optio. Ea, facilis, possimus dolor nobis explicabo recusandae numquam ducimus minus eum totam odio architecto nesciunt accusamus expedita natus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xen Networking</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-09-07-xen-networking</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 15:18:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-09-07-xen-networking</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:trebuchet ms;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I&#39;ve been working on evaluating Xen for all the reasons most companies look into virtualization.      One of the most confusing parts of Xen to learn is the way it does networking.   This is because the Xen team has devised a default configuration that is quite flexible, but also takes some time to get used to.   I&#39;m not even going to talk about that, because I think there&#39;s  a better way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is a description of how to set up networking for Xen on CentOS 5.0 using 802.1q VLAN trunking with a bridge on dom0 for each VLAN.   In my setup, eth0 is dedicated to dom0 tasks like live migration, iSCSI, and console access.    eth1 is dedicated as a VLAN trunk.   NO VLAN interfaces are configured with addresses in dom0, which should help reduce security implications.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Files:&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  DEVICE=eth0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;BOOTPROTO=static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;BROADCAST=192.168.1.255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;HWADDR=00:19:D1:4D:CD:D1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;IPADDR=192.168.1.25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;NETMASK=255.255.255.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;NETWORK=192.168.1.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ONBOOT=yes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;DEVICE=eth1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;HWADDR=00:19:D1:4D:CD:D2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ONBOOT=yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;# note, no address configured&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth1.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;DEVICE=eth1.4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;BOOTPROTO=static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ONBOOT=yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;VLAN=yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;BRIDGE=br4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;# again, no address configured&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;/etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-br4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;DEVICE=br4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;TYPE=Bridge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;BOOTPROTO=static&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ONBOOT=yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;DELAY=0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;STP=off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The files above only demonstrate the standard way to configure 802.1q VLAN&#39;s and bridges under modern Redhat-derivative distributions like RHEL, CentOS, and Fedora.  The nice part is, we&#39;re almost done.    Only a small change is necessary in Xen, so that it no longer brings up xenbr0.  I don&#39;t want to pay for the overhead of networking through a bridge for my iSCSI, even if it is a very small cost.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Modify &lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;/etc/xen/xend-config.sxp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and change &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;(network-script ...)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34; to &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;(network-script /bin/true)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;.    Comment the &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;(vif-script ...)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34; line(s) out completely.   You don&#39;t need them anymore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reboot dom0.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When the box comes back up, log in and look around at your networking configuration.  Use &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34; or &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;ip link show&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;, &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;brctl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;, and &#34;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;cat /proc/net/vlan/config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#34;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Modify your VM configurations to point at the correct bridges.   Something like the following should work fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:85%;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    vif = [ &#39;mac=00:16:3e:01:fb:fe, bridge=br4&#39; ]&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;xend will still create the point-to-point (vif) interfaces and connect them to the bridge for you.   It doesn&#39;t need the helper scripts because the bridges are already all set up and ready to have interfaces bound to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is currently a bit outside the beaten path for Xen netw0rking, so you get to keep all the pieces if it breaks things, has an affair with your refrigerator, or any other such sideeffects.    If you have questions, leave comments on this post and I&#39;ll try to answer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:courier new;&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;undefined&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Niels Wijnja
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2007-09-24T21:54:00.000Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    Very useful information, thanks for that :)
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving sucks.</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-05-20-moving-sucks-can-i-have-amen</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 03:30:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-05-20-moving-sucks-can-i-have-amen</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Well, I&#39;m all moved in to the apartment in San Diego.      Almost, that is.    My belongings are in the space, but as it goes, it&#39;s all still in boxes and it&#39;s a daunting task to go through and organize everything.   Most importantly, though, I&#39;m missing my wife and pets.   In both senses of &#34;missing.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Life the last month has been interesting.    My Vehicross blew up.   I&#39;m in the process of figuring out what to do with it right now and will probably sell it.    It did provide me an excuse to buy a new motorcycle, so I got a brand-new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.suzukicycles.com/Products/DL650K7/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;Suzuki V-Strom 650&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(a.k.a. the &#34;Wee-Strom&#34;).    I enjoyed riding my previous bike, a 1981 Kawasaki 440LTD, but this bike is an absolute dream as far as upgrades go!     So, it is really helping fight off the depression that comes with losing a beloved vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My job is awesome and I&#39;m learning a ton about how to work on a massive scale and how the MMO game industry works.     Linux and Perl still shine as the best hammer any guy could have a toolbox full of.    I&#39;m blown away by how cool and accessible everybody is at work.    I&#39;m so used to the extremely conservative atmosphere, that I still have a hard time adjusting to the relaxed environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m spending some time reimplementing some tools similar to what I had at my old job because they really did make life better.    One is a nice wrapper around CGI::Application and some of its plugins (like Plugin::TT and Plugin::AutoRunmode) to make writing one-off apps very fast and efficient.    I looked at Catalyst &amp;amp; co. but they&#39;re just too darned much infrastructure for the kinds of apps I&#39;m writing.     I also couldn&#39;t get a handle on what the future is for Catalyst.   It looks like Maypole is pretty much rolled into Catalyst (I could be wrong, so don&#39;t quote me).    I didn&#39;t see anything else compelling out there as far as Perl goes.    Django looked good, but I still have a hard time reaching for Python.   It&#39;s not my usual language bigotry - it&#39;s common sense this time.    I&#39;m so busy already that taking time to learn another language isn&#39;t in the cards right now.     I know these things have 20-minute tutorials, but I also have to consider the fact that all the other sysadmins I know, know Perl.      Very few know Python or any other language for that matter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other Perl-related news, I&#39;m looking for somebody to take over maintenance on Nagios::Object on CPAN.    I really enjoyed getting it out there, but it&#39;s tough keeping up with the updates to Nagios these days since I don&#39;t have any installations that I work on.      Just drop a mail to tobert@gmail.com and we&#39;ll talk about it.   There is a queue of updates that I need to get out but haven&#39;t had the time to get them all wrapped up and tested so I can make a release.   I guess I&#39;ll just have to throw it together and put it out there so people can beat on it...
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Job, New City</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-04-04-new-job-new-city</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 14:18:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-04-04-new-job-new-city</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
I&#39;ve been putting off shutting down tobert.org because I&#39;ve been really busy with another project: finding a new job.   I applied and interviewed at four well-known technical companies on the west coast and accepted an offer from Sony Online Entertainment on April 2, 2007.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was a weird experience for me, having mostly applied for standard corporate jobs in West Michigan in the past.   Actually, I&#39;ve never had multiple offers before which made the decision process difficult.     Any one of these companies would be awesome to work for.   All of the people were extremely smart and passionate.     I spent the entire weekend driving my wife, family, and my friends crazy talking incessantly about what to do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What it came down to was my gut reaction towards the companies and the cities they were in.   A lot of people might think I&#39;m full of it when I say it, but money was not the object.     I didn&#39;t take the highest paying job even after rolling in cost of living differences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I ended up asking myself some &#34;soft&#34; questions:&lt;br /&gt;- abstract the job from the company and its reputation; do I still like it?&lt;br /&gt;- would I choose the city regardless of job and income?   Would Krissy (my wife)?&lt;br /&gt;- what does the professional and community theatre community look like for Krissy?&lt;br /&gt;- do I like the physical environment (desk/workstation/lighting/dress code/etc.)?&lt;br /&gt;- do I feel comfortable with the political environment?&lt;br /&gt;- is there opportunity to make things better?   Is it cleanup or creation?&lt;br /&gt;- what career options are available in the next 5 years?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyways, I&#39;m not going to mention the names of the other three companies.    I don&#39;t want anybody to think they&#39;re not awesome companies to work for, because that would be untrue.    I would work at any one of them and it has been both a burden and an honor to choose between them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In case you&#39;re somebody looking for tips on interviewing, here&#39;s the most important and non-obvious-to-me lesson I learned.    Think really hard about whether or not to reveal the names and offers from other companies to your recruiters.     It may mean better offers, it might not.     It can also cause some other side effects that I found less than pleasant, so in the future, I&#39;m going to keep my big mouth shut.     Somebody warned me and they were right, so if you ever read this, you&#39;re welcome to your &#34;I told you so.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, I have to say goodbye to six years at Priority Health.    They accepted my resignation with dignity and warm wishes, which I truly appreciate.    I will miss my friends there and wish them all the best.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comments-content js-full-comments-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/09138352142189162260&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    brimyn
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2007-04-04T15:09:00.000Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    I know a new job AND a new city is a tremendous effort, risk, and time of uncertainty.  You&#39;ll do great.  Congratulations and best of luck!
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/02840519174487803262&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Rick
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2007-04-06T00:18:00.000Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    Al, Good luck and God Speed.&lt;BR/&gt;&lt;BR/&gt;I enjoyed working with you for the majority of those 6 years.  You have a tremendous set of talents of a wide variety.  I wish you all the best!
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-comment js-full-comment&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-user-link js-comment-user-link&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/10270471525388458692&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-name js-comment-name&#34;&gt;
    Keith Hinkle
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-date js-comment-date&#34;&gt;
    2007-04-27T13:47:00.000Z
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;css-comment-content js-comment-content&#34;&gt;
    congrats!!!  i&#39;ll miss you here.  i look forward to seeing you new postings.&lt;BR/&gt;&lt;BR/&gt;did rick not enjoy working with you for a minority time of the six years :-)?&lt;BR/&gt;&lt;BR/&gt;god bless,&lt;BR/&gt;keith
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-02-27-hi-my-name-is-al-tobey</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 00:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-02-27-hi-my-name-is-al-tobey</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Hi, my name is Al Tobey.    For now, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tobert.org&#34;&gt;http://www.tobert.org&lt;/a&gt; to learn the grossly-out-of-date details.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m investigating whether or not I want to move &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tobert.org&#34;&gt;http://www.tobert.org&lt;/a&gt; to Blogger.    I&#39;m doing it to save time/money and to take advantage of integration between the various Google tools, where it exists.   I&#39;ve also often considered posting more often, which I avoid because my current setup is still a PITA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The main snag I&#39;m working on right now is how to post code examples.   So far, it looks like nobody is really doing it well.    Most of the &#34;solutions&#34; I&#39;ve found involve stuff like &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: monospace;&#34;&gt;sed &#39;s/ /\&amp;amp;nbsp;/g&#39;&lt;/span&gt;, which isn&#39;t very elegant when HTML has tags specifically for this kind of thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Previously, I defaulted to using the &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt; tag for code examples.   So far, I&#39;ve tried &amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;p style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&amp;gt; (which I learned about at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.htmldog.com/ptg/archives/000077.php&#34;&gt;http://www.htmldog.com/ptg/archives/000077.php&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyways, I&#39;m going to keep editing this post adding copies of the below code until it works.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;#!/bin/ksh&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;for file in *.html&lt;br /&gt;do&lt;br /&gt;    # this should be indented by 4 spaces&lt;br /&gt;    sed &#39;s/ /\&amp;amp;nbsp;/g&#39; &lt; &#34;$file&#34; &gt; &#34;$file.new&#34;&lt;br /&gt;    mv &#34;$file.new&#34; &#34;$file&#34;&lt;br /&gt;done&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem solved:&lt;/strong&gt;:   It appears that &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt; is ignored in the preview you get in the edit posts view, but not on the published page.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorem Ipsum</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/lorem-ipsum</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/lorem-ipsum</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis mattis ante eget porttitor dignissim. Suspendisse commodo leo at erat tincidunt ullamcorper. Etiam sagittis sem nisl, nec tincidunt magna mollis sed. Integer elementum viverra est, nec imperdiet lacus gravida non. Sed eget neque et augue lacinia ultrices eget sed odio. Praesent feugiat, velit sed fringilla malesuada, mauris dolor congue odio, vel mollis dolor ipsum condimentum sapien. Morbi in velit ut odio cursus tempus id sit amet nulla. Praesent laoreet eros eget iaculis fringilla. Aenean quis massa ligula. Maecenas pulvinar mauris eget sapien fermentum accumsan. Ut venenatis leo at elit facilisis pellentesque. Praesent volutpat est et lorem gravida, in ultrices lorem tincidunt. Ut at massa mollis, fermentum dolor sit amet, gravida nulla. Praesent condimentum tincidunt est a consequat. Aenean vehicula nisi id enim iaculis faucibus.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Vivamus vel luctus augue. Nulla cursus volutpat urna suscipit egestas. Quisque tempus iaculis tortor a suscipit. In dapibus quam sed odio ullamcorper, eget dictum metus egestas. Nullam posuere dui vitae felis tincidunt convallis. Integer non ligula sed lectus porttitor ultricies at ut nibh. Vivamus non orci venenatis, interdum augue quis, aliquam enim.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Integer consectetur tortor a pellentesque tincidunt. Vestibulum viverra mauris erat, in auctor nibh ultrices ac. Quisque sapien magna, sagittis nec euismod sit amet, vehicula in nisi. Etiam nunc orci, euismod id lectus ut, condimentum hendrerit eros. Mauris blandit magna libero. Donec varius augue justo, ut cursus arcu volutpat non. Nam at erat massa. Donec purus leo, lobortis eu consequat eu, feugiat a erat. Nullam adipiscing sapien eget gravida tincidunt. Morbi feugiat vitae metus at iaculis. Morbi rutrum ligula at arcu lobortis interdum. Ut quis ante in enim molestie fringilla. Sed malesuada pellentesque ligula. Ut consectetur, neque vitae ornare vehicula, sem elit auctor urna, nec elementum magna dolor nec risus.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Praesent tincidunt tincidunt velit et volutpat. Duis a velit ante. Suspendisse sit amet enim sit amet est convallis mollis non mattis risus. Nulla sagittis, orci ac varius cursus, lectus lacus pharetra erat, nec iaculis lorem mi scelerisque orci. Maecenas a ullamcorper augue, ut luctus eros. Duis orci justo, feugiat vel diam a, fringilla condimentum sem. Vestibulum eu dictum tellus. Pellentesque vel dolor massa. Nullam erat nulla, pellentesque at metus nec, vehicula commodo nisl. Fusce fermentum justo vel dolor semper vehicula. Sed et pharetra turpis. Donec id enim quam. In tempus venenatis eros eu pellentesque. Curabitur feugiat eros cursus, venenatis nibh a, tincidunt mi. Pellentesque blandit tortor ac mauris aliquam ullamcorper.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Phasellus vitae condimentum lacus. Cras dapibus metus imperdiet orci porta, et auctor massa volutpat. Phasellus ultricies feugiat dolor vel blandit. Fusce ullamcorper sem id nisl bibendum, ut pulvinar mauris pellentesque. Suspendisse accumsan tristique metus eget suscipit. Ut porta gravida ultricies. Integer in massa eu erat gravida lobortis nec ut elit. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Praesent tincidunt purus in elementum interdum. Suspendisse potenti. Aliquam mattis ipsum in eros tempus interdum. Pellentesque eleifend magna vel metus elementum interdum et ut orci. Suspendisse lectus erat, egestas at dignissim et, posuere vel libero.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>64-bit perl on HP-UX (PARISC or Itanium)</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2005-10-13-64-bit-perl-on-hp-ux-parisc-or-itanium</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2005 02:30:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2005-10-13-64-bit-perl-on-hp-ux-parisc-or-itanium</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Here&#39;s something that took me a few hours to get dialed in.    This is all set for linking DBD::Oracle and DBD::Sybase to their respective 64-bit client libraries without hassle.   I&#39;m assuming the HP ANSI C compiler is installed.   I never even tried with gcc due to some custom extensions that require the HP compiler.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CC=/opt/ansic/bin/cc \&lt;br /&gt;CXX=/opt/aCC/bin/aCC \&lt;br /&gt;CFLAGS=&#34;+DD64 +Z -I/opt/perl-5.8/local/include&#34; \&lt;br /&gt;CXXFLAGS=$CFLAGS \&lt;br /&gt;LDFLAGS=&#34;-L/opt/perl-5.8/local/lib -L/usr/lib/hpux64&#34; \&lt;br /&gt;PATH=/opt/ansic/bin:/usr/ccs/bin:/opt/perl-5.8/local/bin:/opt/perl-5.8/bin:/usr/bin:/usr/local/bin:/bin:/sbin \&lt;br /&gt;PERL=/opt/perl-5.8/bin/perl \ &lt;br /&gt;MAKE=/usr/local/bin/gmake \&lt;br /&gt;./Configure -der \&lt;br /&gt;            -A prepend:libswanted=&#39;cl pthread &#39; \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dprefix=/opt/perl-5.8 \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dinstallprefix=/opt/perl-5.8 \&lt;br /&gt;            -Duselargefiles \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dusethreads \&lt;br /&gt;            -Duse64bitall \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dyacc=&#39;/usr/local/bin/bison -y&#39; \&lt;br /&gt;            -Uusemallocwrap \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dcf_by=&#34;Al Tobey&#34; \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dperladmin=&#39;tobert@gmail.com&#39; \&lt;br /&gt;            -Dcf_email=&#39;tobert@gmail.com&#39;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;make&lt;br /&gt;make test&lt;br /&gt;make install&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(cd /usr/include; /opt/perl-5.8/bin/h2ph -r -l .)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pdksh-5</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2005-09-20-pdksh-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 23:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2005-09-20-pdksh-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
pdksh 5.2.14 on HP-UX 11.23 Itanium: If you grab the source for pdksh and try to compile it on Itanium HP-UX, it will tend to dump core with SIGBUS. SIGBUS is a signal sent to processes when they access unaligned memory, usually in C unions or structs. pdksh has a union in it that ends up unaligned on Itanium, which is very particular about such things. HP-UX is also fussy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Go into the source tree and open up &#34;alloc.c&#34; in your favorite editor. Search for &#34;union Cell&#34;, which is the union declaration that is causing the trouble. Change the last member &#34;double djunk; /* alignement */&#34; to &#34;long double djunk; /* alignemnt */.&#34; On Itanic, long double is 128 bits and double is 64 bits. Pushing the union out to 128 bits makes it align right all the time, even though it does eat up a bit more memory now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also have a patch at work that logs all commands run by root to syslog with the username of the owner of the terminal device.   It&#39;s a fancy way to avoid typing &#34;sudo&#34; in front of everything while still logging every command for auditing purposes.    Unfortunately, I probably can&#39;t post that patch.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>root-tail on nautilus/kde/xfdesktop</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2004-07-01-i-hacked-root-tail-to-work-with</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 01:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2004-07-01-i-hacked-root-tail-to-work-with</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;boldunder&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I hacked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goof.com/pcg/marc/root-tail.html&#34;&gt;root-tail&lt;/a&gt; to work with Nautilus, KDE, and hopefully XFCE4&#39;s xfdesktop.  I took the toon_root.c file from &lt;a href=&#34;http://xpenguins.seul.org/&#34;&gt;xpenguins&lt;/a&gt; and :r&#39;d it into root-tail.c.  A few modifications later and I had a working root-tail for nautilus.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Download the tarball: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/root-tail-xpenguins.tar.gz&#34;&gt;root-tail-xpenguins.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt; or just &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/root-tail.c&#34;&gt;root-tail.c&lt;/a&gt;. Here it is in HTML: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/root-tail.c.html&#34;&gt;root-tail.c.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/screenshot-gnome-root-tail.jpg&#34;&gt;Screenshot (40k)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i-wrote-couple-snmp-plugins-for-nagios</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2004-06-30-i-wrote-couple-snmp-plugins-for-nagios</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2004 19:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2004-06-30-i-wrote-couple-snmp-plugins-for-nagios</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;boldunder&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I wrote a couple SNMP plugins for Nagios to check disk space and running processes. They are now in the contrib directory in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nagiosplug.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Nagios Plugins&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;br /&gt;They both should work on Windows 2000 (and up) and Novell. HP-UX, unfortunately, does not ship with the Host-Resource MIB by default, so I&#39;m using the Net-SNMP daemon at work. It&#39;s a little flakey, but gets the job done. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snmpresearch.com/&#34;&gt;SNMP Research&lt;/a&gt; provides an extended SNMP daemon for HP-UX and other operating systems that includes the host resource MIB.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m also author and maintainer of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.cpan.org/%7Etobeya/Nagios-Object/&#34;&gt;Nagios::Object&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.cpan.org/%7Etobeya/Nagios-Cmd/&#34;&gt;Nagios::Cmd&lt;/a&gt; modules on &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.cpan.org/&#34;&gt;CPAN&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>here-is-drop-in-replacement-for-rajeev</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2003-12-02-here-is-drop-in-replacement-for-rajeev</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2003 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2003-12-02-here-is-drop-in-replacement-for-rajeev</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Here is a drop-in replacement for Rajeev Kumar&#39;s bootprofile, written in (bourne|korn|posix) shell. Everything required [on my rh9/rawhide laptop] is in /bin or /sbin. It&#39;s nice when you like to put everything on separate LVM volumes like I do. Here it is: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/bootprofile.sh&#34;&gt;bootprofile.sh&lt;/a&gt;. View now: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/bootprofile.sh.txt&#34;&gt;bootprofile.sh.txt&lt;/a&gt;. Last update: December 02, 2003.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tobert.googlepages.com/bootprofile-sc.jpg&#34;&gt;Screenshot (46k)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
