<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:creativeCommons="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html"
     xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#"
     xmlns:xapRights="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/rights/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vstrom on @AlTobey Writes </title>
    <link>https://tobert.github.io/tags/vstrom/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
	<pubDate>2010-02-02 05:38:39 -0700 -0700</pubDate>
	<lastBuildDate>2010-02-02 05:38:39 -0700 -0700</lastBuildDate>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving sucks.</title>
      <link>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-05-20-moving-sucks-can-i-have-amen</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 05:38:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Albert P Tobey</author>
      <guid>https://tobert.github.io/post/2007-05-20-moving-sucks-can-i-have-amen</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;css-full-post-content js-full-post-content&#34;&gt;
Well, I&#39;m all moved in to the apartment in San Diego.      Almost, that is.    My belongings are in the space, but as it goes, it&#39;s all still in boxes and it&#39;s a daunting task to go through and organize everything.   Most importantly, though, I&#39;m missing my wife and pets.   In both senses of &#34;missing.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Life the last month has been interesting.    My Vehicross blew up.   I&#39;m in the process of figuring out what to do with it right now and will probably sell it.    It did provide me an excuse to buy a new motorcycle, so I got a brand-new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.suzukicycles.com/Products/DL650K7/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;Suzuki V-Strom 650&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(a.k.a. the &#34;Wee-Strom&#34;).    I enjoyed riding my previous bike, a 1981 Kawasaki 440LTD, but this bike is an absolute dream as far as upgrades go!     So, it is really helping fight off the depression that comes with losing a beloved vehicle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My job is awesome and I&#39;m learning a ton about how to work on a massive scale and how the MMO game industry works.     Linux and Perl still shine as the best hammer any guy could have a toolbox full of.    I&#39;m blown away by how cool and accessible everybody is at work.    I&#39;m so used to the extremely conservative atmosphere, that I still have a hard time adjusting to the relaxed environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;m spending some time reimplementing some tools similar to what I had at my old job because they really did make life better.    One is a nice wrapper around CGI::Application and some of its plugins (like Plugin::TT and Plugin::AutoRunmode) to make writing one-off apps very fast and efficient.    I looked at Catalyst &amp;amp; co. but they&#39;re just too darned much infrastructure for the kinds of apps I&#39;m writing.     I also couldn&#39;t get a handle on what the future is for Catalyst.   It looks like Maypole is pretty much rolled into Catalyst (I could be wrong, so don&#39;t quote me).    I didn&#39;t see anything else compelling out there as far as Perl goes.    Django looked good, but I still have a hard time reaching for Python.   It&#39;s not my usual language bigotry - it&#39;s common sense this time.    I&#39;m so busy already that taking time to learn another language isn&#39;t in the cards right now.     I know these things have 20-minute tutorials, but I also have to consider the fact that all the other sysadmins I know, know Perl.      Very few know Python or any other language for that matter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other Perl-related news, I&#39;m looking for somebody to take over maintenance on Nagios::Object on CPAN.    I really enjoyed getting it out there, but it&#39;s tough keeping up with the updates to Nagios these days since I don&#39;t have any installations that I work on.      Just drop a mail to tobert@gmail.com and we&#39;ll talk about it.   There is a queue of updates that I need to get out but haven&#39;t had the time to get them all wrapped up and tested so I can make a release.   I guess I&#39;ll just have to throw it together and put it out there so people can beat on it...
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
